[{"qid": "T1A01", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following is a purpose of the Amateur Radio Service as stated in the FCC rules and regulations?", "options": {"A": "Providing personal radio communications for as many citizens as possible", "B": "Providing communications for international non-profit organizations", "C": "Advancing skills in the technical and communication phases of the radio art", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T1A02", "answer": "C", "question": "Which agency regulates and enforces the rules for the Amateur Radio Service in the United States?", "options": {"A": "FEMA", "B": "The ITU", "C": "The FCC", "D": "Homeland Security"}}, {"qid": "T1A03", "answer": "D", "question": "Which part of the FCC regulations contains the rules governing the Amateur Radio Service?", "options": {"A": "Part 73", "B": "Part 95", "C": "Part 90", "D": "Part 97"}}, {"qid": "T1A04", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following meets the FCC definition of harmful interference?", "options": {"A": "Radio transmissions that annoy users of a repeater", "B": "Unwanted radio transmissions that cause costly harm to radio station apparatus", "C": "That which seriously degrades, obstructs, or repeatedly interrupts a radio communication service operating in accordance with the Radio Regulations", "D": "Static from lightning storms"}}, {"qid": "T1A05", "answer": "A", "question": "Which of the following is a purpose of the Amateur Radio Service rules and regulations as defined by the FCC?", "options": {"A": "Enhancing international goodwill", "B": "Providing inexpensive communication for local emergency organizations", "C": "Training of operators in military radio operating procedures", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T1A06", "answer": "D", "question": "D.\ufffdRadionavigation Service", "options": {"A": "Citizens Radio Service", "C": "Land Mobile Radio Service"}}, {"qid": "T1A07", "answer": "C", "question": "What is the FCC Part 97 definition of telemetry?", "options": {"A": "An information bulletin issued by the FCC", "B": "A one-way transmission to initiate, modify or terminate functions of a device at a distance", "C": "A one-way transmission of measurements at a distance from the measuring instrument", "D": "An information bulletin from a VEC"}}, {"qid": "T1A08", "answer": "B", "question": "Which of the following entities recommends transmit/receive channels and other parameters for auxiliary and repeater stations?", "options": {"A": "Frequency Spectrum Manager", "B": "Frequency Coordinator", "C": "FCC Regional Field Office", "D": "International Telecommunications Union"}}, {"qid": "T1A09", "answer": "C", "question": "Who selects a Frequency Coordinator?", "options": {"A": "The FCC Office of Spectrum Management and Coordination Policy", "B": "The local chapter of the Office of National Council of Independent Frequency Coordinators", "C": "Amateur operators in a local or regional area whose stations are eligible to be auxiliary or repeater stations", "D": "FCC Regional Field Office"}}, {"qid": "T1A10", "answer": "A", "question": "What is the FCC Part 97 definition of an amateur station?", "options": {"A": "A station in the Amateur Radio Service consisting of the apparatus necessary for carrying on radio communications", "B": "A building where Amateur Radio receivers, transmitters, and RF power amplifiers are installed", "C": "Any radio station operated by a non-professional", "D": "Any radio station for hobby use"}}, {"qid": "T1A11", "answer": "B", "question": "When is willful interference to other amateur radio stations permitted?", "options": {"A": "Only if the station being interfered with is expressing extreme religious or political views", "B": "At no time", "C": "Only during a contest", "D": "At any time, amateurs are not protected from willful interference"}}, {"qid": "T1A12", "answer": "D", "question": "Which of the following is a permissible use of the Amateur Radio Service?", "options": {"A": "Broadcasting music and videos to friends", "B": "Providing a way for amateur radio operators to earn additional income by using their stations to pass messages", "C": "Providing low-cost communications for start-up businesses", "D": "Allowing a person to conduct radio experiments and to communicate with other licensed hams around the world"}}, {"qid": "T1A13", "answer": "C", "question": "What is the FCC Part 97 definition of telecommand?", "options": {"A": "An instruction bulletin issued by the FCC", "B": "A one-way radio transmission of measurements at a distance from the measuring instrument", "C": "A one-way transmission to initiate, modify or terminate functions of a device at a distance", "D": "An instruction from a VEC"}}, {"qid": "T1A14", "answer": "A", "question": "What must you do if you are operating on the 23 cm band and learn that you are interfering with a radiolocation station outside the United States?", "options": {"A": "Stop operating or take steps to eliminate the harmful interference", "B": "Nothing, because this band is allocated exclusively to the amateur service", "C": "Establish contact with the radiolocation station and ask them to change frequency", "D": "Change to CW mode, because this would not likely cause interference"}}, {"qid": "T1B01", "answer": "B", "question": "What is the ITU?", "options": {"A": "An agency of the United States Department of Telecommunications Management", "B": "A United Nations agency for information and communication technology issues", "C": "An independent frequency coordination agency", "D": "A department of the FCC"}}, {"qid": "T1B02", "answer": "A", "question": "Why are the frequency assignments for some U.S. Territories different from those in the 50 U.S. States?", "options": {"A": "Some U. S. Territories are located in ITU regions other than region 2", "B": "Territorial governments are allowed to select their own frequency allocations", "C": "Territorial frequency allocations must also include those of adjacent countries", "D": "Any territory that was in existence before the ratification of the Communications Act of 1934 is exempt from FCC frequency regulations"}}, {"qid": "T1B03", "answer": "B", "question": "Which frequency is within the 6 meter band?", "options": {"A": "49.00 MHz", "B": "52.525 MHz", "C": "28.50 MHz", "D": "222.15 MHz"}}, {"qid": "T1B04", "answer": "A", "question": "Which amateur band are you using when your station is transmitting on 146.52 MHz?", "options": {"A": "2 meter band", "B": "20 meter band", "C": "14 meter band", "D": "6 meter band"}}, {"qid": "T1B05", "answer": "C", "question": "Which 70 cm frequency is authorized to a Technician Class license holder operating in ITU Region 2?", "options": {"A": "53.350 MHz", "B": "146.520 MHz", "C": "443.350 MHz", "D": "222.520 MHz"}}, {"qid": "T1B06", "answer": "B", "question": "Which 23 cm frequency is authorized to a Technician Class licensee?", "options": {"A": "2315 MHz", "B": "1296 MHz", "C": "3390 MHz", "D": "146.52 MHz"}}, {"qid": "T1B07", "answer": "D", "question": "What amateur band are you using if you are transmitting on 223.50 MHz?", "options": {"A": "15 meter band", "B": "10 meter band", "C": "2 meter band", "D": "1.25 meter band"}}, {"qid": "T1B08", "answer": "A", "question": "Which of the following is a result of the fact that the amateur service is secondary in some portions of the 70 cm band?", "options": {"A": "U.S. amateurs may find non-amateur stations in the bands, and must avoid interfering with them", "B": "U.S. amateurs must give foreign amateur stations priority in those portions", "C": "International communications are not permitted on 70 cm", "D": "Digital transmissions are not permitted on 70 cm"}}, {"qid": "T1B09", "answer": "D", "question": "Why should you not set your transmit frequency to be exactly at the edge of an amateur band or sub-band?", "options": {"A": "To allow for calibration error in the transmitter frequency display", "B": "So that modulation sidebands do not extend beyond the band edge", "C": "To allow for transmitter frequency drift", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T1B10", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the bands above 30 MHz that are available to Technician Class operators have mode-restricted sub-bands?", "options": {"A": "The 6 meter, 2 meter, and 70 cm bands", "B": "The 2 meter and 13 cm bands", "C": "The 6 meter, 2 meter, and 1.25 meter bands", "D": "The 2 meter and 70 cm bands"}}, {"qid": "T1B11", "answer": "A", "question": "What emission modes are permitted in the mode-restricted sub-bands at 50.0 to 50.1 MHz and 144.0 to 144.1 MHz?", "options": {"A": "CW only", "B": "CW and RTTY", "C": "SSB only", "D": "CW and SSB"}}, {"qid": "T1B12", "answer": "B", "question": "A.\ufffdAmateur maritime mobile stations in international waters must conform to the frequency assignments of the country nearest to their vessel", "options": {"B": "Amateur frequency assignments can vary among the three ITU regions", "C": "Frequency assignments are determined by the captain of the vessel", "D": "Amateur frequency assignments are different in each of the 90 ITU zones"}}, {"qid": "T1B13", "answer": "B", "question": "Which emission may be used between 219 and 220 MHz?", "options": {"A": "Spread spectrum", "B": "Data", "C": "SSB voice", "D": "Fast-scan television"}}, {"qid": "T1C01", "answer": "C", "question": "Which type of call sign has a single letter in both its prefix and suffix?", "options": {"A": "Vanity", "B": "Sequential", "C": "Special event", "D": "In-memoriam"}}, {"qid": "T1C02", "answer": "B", "question": "Which of the following is a valid US amateur radio station call sign?", "options": {"A": "KMA3505", "B": "W3ABC", "C": "KDKA", "D": "11Q1176"}}, {"qid": "T1C03", "answer": "A", "question": "What types of international communications are permitted by an FCC-licensed amateur station?", "options": {"A": "Communications incidental to the purposes of the amateur service and remarks of a personal character", "B": "Communications incidental to conducting business or remarks of a personal nature", "C": "Only communications incidental to contest exchanges, all other communications are prohibited", "D": "Any communications that would be permitted by an international broadcast station"}}, {"qid": "T1C04", "answer": "A", "question": "When are you allowed to operate your amateur station in a foreign country?", "options": {"A": "When the foreign country authorizes it", "B": "When there is a mutual agreement allowing third party communications", "C": "When authorization permits amateur communications in a foreign language", "D": "When you are communicating with non-licensed individuals in another country"}}, {"qid": "T1C05", "answer": "A", "question": "Which of the following is a vanity call sign which a technician class amateur operator might select if available?", "options": {"A": "K1XXX", "B": "KA1X", "C": "W1XX", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T1C06", "answer": "D", "question": "From which of the following locations may an FCC-licensed amateur station transmit, in addition to places where the FCC regulates communications?", "options": {"A": "From within any country that belongs to the International Telecommunications Union", "B": "From within any country that is a member of the United Nations", "C": "From anywhere within in ITU Regions 2 and 3", "D": "From any vessel or craft located in international waters and documented or registered in the United States"}}, {"qid": "T1C07", "answer": "B", "question": "What may result when correspondence from the FCC is returned as undeliverable because the grantee failed to provide the correct mailing address?", "options": {"A": "Fine or imprisonment", "B": "Revocation of the station license or suspension of the operator license", "C": "Require the licensee to be re-examined", "D": "A reduction of one rank in operator class"}}, {"qid": "T1C08", "answer": "C", "question": "What is the normal term for an FCC-issued primary station/operator amateur radio license grant?", "options": {"A": "Five years", "B": "Life", "C": "Ten years", "D": "Twenty years"}}, {"qid": "T1C09", "answer": "A", "question": "What is the grace period following the expiration of an amateur license within which the license may be renewed?", "options": {"A": "Two years", "B": "Three years", "C": "Five years", "D": "Ten years"}}, {"qid": "T1C10", "answer": "C", "question": "How soon after passing the examination for your first amateur radio license may you operate a transmitter on an amateur service frequency?", "options": {"A": "Immediately", "B": "30 days after the test date", "C": "As soon as your operator/station license grant appears in the FCC\ufffds license database", "D": "You must wait until you receive your license in the mail from the FCC"}}, {"qid": "T1C11", "answer": "A", "question": "If your license has expired and is still within the allowable grace period, may you continue to operate a transmitter on amateur service frequencies?", "options": {"A": "No, transmitting is not allowed until the FCC license database shows that the license has been renewed", "B": "Yes, but only if you identify using the suffix GP", "C": "Yes, but only during authorized nets", "D": "Yes, for up to two years"}}, {"qid": "T1C12", "answer": "D", "question": "Who may select a desired call sign under the vanity call sign rules?", "options": {"A": "Only licensed amateurs with general or extra class licenses", "B": "Only licensed amateurs with an extra class license", "C": "Only an amateur licensee who has been licensed continuously for more than 10 years", "D": "Any licensed amateur"}}, {"qid": "T1C13", "answer": "D", "question": "For which licenses classes are new licenses currently available from the FCC?", "options": {"A": "Novice, Technician, General, Advanced", "B": "Technician, Technician Plus, General, Advanced", "C": "Novice, Technician Plus, General, Advanced", "D": "Technician, General, Amateur Extra"}}, {"qid": "T1C14", "answer": "D", "question": "Who may select a vanity call sign for a club station?", "options": {"A": "Any Extra Class member of the club", "B": "Any member of the club", "C": "Any officer of the club", "D": "Only the person named as trustee on the club station license grant"}}, {"qid": "T1D01", "answer": "A", "question": "With which countries are FCC-licensed amateur stations prohibited from exchanging communications?", "options": {"A": "Any country whose administration has notified the ITU that it objects to such communications", "B": "Any country whose administration has notified the ARRL that it objects to such communications", "C": "Any country engaged in hostilities with another country", "D": "Any country in violation of the War Powers Act of 1934"}}, {"qid": "T1D02", "answer": "A", "question": "On which of the following occasions may an FCC-licensed amateur station exchange messages with a U.S. military station?", "options": {"A": "During an Armed Forces Day Communications Test", "B": "During a Memorial Day Celebration", "C": "During an Independence Day celebration", "D": "During a propagation test"}}, {"qid": "T1D03", "answer": "C", "question": "When is the transmission of codes or ciphers that hide the meaning of a message allowed by an amateur station?", "options": {"A": "Only during contests", "B": "Only when operating mobile", "C": "Only when transmitting control commands to space stations or radio control craft", "D": "Only when frequencies above 1280 MHz are used"}}, {"qid": "T1D04", "answer": "A", "question": "What is the only time an amateur station is authorized to transmit music?", "options": {"A": "When incidental to an authorized retransmission of manned spacecraft communications", "B": "When the music produces no spurious emissions", "C": "When the purpose is to interfere with an illegal transmission", "D": "When the music is transmitted above 1280 MHz"}}, {"qid": "T1D05", "answer": "A", "question": "When may amateur radio operators use their stations to notify other amateurs of the availability of equipment for sale or trade?", "options": {"A": "When the equipment is normally used in an amateur station and such activity is not conducted on a regular basis", "B": "When the asking price is $100.00 or less", "C": "When the asking price is less than its appraised value", "D": "When the equipment is not the personal property of either the station licensee or the control operator or their close relatives"}}, {"qid": "T1D06", "answer": "B", "question": "What, if any, are the restrictions concerning transmission of language that may be considered indecent or obscene?", "options": {"A": "The FCC maintains a list of words that are not permitted to be used on amateur frequencies", "B": "Any such language is prohibited", "C": "The ITU maintains a list of words that are not permitted to be used on amateur frequencies", "D": "There is no such prohibition"}}, {"qid": "T1D07", "answer": "B", "question": "What types of amateur stations can automatically retransmit the signals of other amateur stations?", "options": {"A": "Auxiliary, beacon, or Earth stations", "B": "Auxiliary, repeater, or space stations", "C": "Beacon, repeater, or space stations", "D": "Earth, repeater, or space stations"}}, {"qid": "T1D08", "answer": "B", "question": "In which of the following circumstances may the control operator of an amateur station receive compensation for operating the station?", "options": {"A": "When engaging in communications on behalf of their employer", "B": "When the communication is incidental to classroom instruction at an educational institution", "C": "When re-broadcasting weather alerts during a RACES net", "D": "When notifying other amateur operators of the availability for sale or trade of apparatus"}}, {"qid": "T1D09", "answer": "A", "question": "Under which of the following circumstances are amateur stations authorized to transmit signals related to broadcasting, program production, or news gathering, assuming no other means is available?", "options": {"A": "Only where such communications directly relate to the immediate safety of human life or protection of property", "B": "Only when broadcasting communications to or from the space shuttle", "C": "Only where noncommercial programming is gathered and supplied exclusively to the National Public Radio network", "D": "Only when using amateur repeaters linked to the Internet"}}, {"qid": "T1D10", "answer": "D", "question": "What is the meaning of the term \ufffdbroadcasting\ufffd in the FCC rules for the amateur services?", "options": {"A": "Two-way transmissions by amateur stations", "B": "Transmission of music", "C": "Transmission of messages directed only to amateur operators", "D": "Transmissions intended for reception by the general public"}}, {"qid": "T1D11", "answer": "D", "question": "When may an amateur station transmit without identifying?", "options": {"A": "When the transmissions are of a brief nature to make station adjustments", "B": "When the transmissions are unmodulated", "C": "When the transmitted power level is below 1 watt", "D": "When transmitting signals to control a model craft"}}, {"qid": "T1D12", "answer": "B", "question": "Under which of the following circumstances may an amateur radio station engage in broadcasting?", "options": {"A": "Under no circumstances", "B": "When transmitting code practice, information bulletins, or transmissions necessary to provide emergency communications", "C": "At any time as long as no music is transmitted", "D": "At any time as long as the material being transmitted did not originate from a commercial broadcast station"}}, {"qid": "T1E01", "answer": "D", "question": "When is an amateur station permitted to transmit without a control operator?", "options": {"A": "When using automatic control, such as in the case of a repeater", "B": "When the station licensee is away and another licensed amateur is using the station", "C": "When the transmitting station is an auxiliary station", "D": "Never"}}, {"qid": "T1E02", "answer": "D", "question": "Who may a station licensee designate to be the control operator of an amateur station?", "options": {"A": "Any U.S. citizen or registered alien", "B": "Any family member of the station licensee", "C": "Any person over the age of 18", "D": "Only a person for whom an amateur operator/primary station license grant appears in the FCC database or who is authorized for alien reciprocal operation"}}, {"qid": "T1E03", "answer": "A", "question": "Who must designate the station control operator?", "options": {"A": "The station licensee", "B": "The FCC", "C": "The frequency coordinator", "D": "The ITU"}}, {"qid": "T1E04", "answer": "D", "question": "What determines the transmitting privileges of an amateur station?", "options": {"A": "The frequency authorized by the frequency coordinator", "B": "The class of operator license held by the station licensee", "C": "The highest class of operator license held by anyone on the premises", "D": "The class of operator license held by the control operator"}}, {"qid": "T1E05", "answer": "C", "question": "What is an amateur station control point?", "options": {"A": "The location of the station\ufffds transmitting antenna", "B": "The location of the station transmitting apparatus", "C": "The location at which the control operator function is performed", "D": "The mailing address of the station licensee"}}, {"qid": "T1E06", "answer": "A", "question": "Under what type of control do APRS network digipeaters operate?", "options": {"A": "Automatic", "B": "Remote", "C": "Local", "D": "Manual"}}, {"qid": "T1E07", "answer": "D", "question": "When the control operator is not the station licensee, who is responsible for the proper operation of the station?", "options": {"A": "All licensed amateurs who are present at the operation", "B": "Only the station licensee", "C": "Only the control operator", "D": "The control operator and the station licensee are equally responsible"}}, {"qid": "T1E08", "answer": "A", "question": "Which of the following is an example of automatic control?", "options": {"A": "Repeater operation", "B": "Controlling the station over the Internet", "C": "Using a computer or other device to automatically send CW", "D": "Using a computer or other device to automatically identify"}}, {"qid": "T1E09", "answer": "D", "question": "What type of control is being used when the control operator is at the control point?", "options": {"A": "Radio control", "B": "Unattended control", "C": "Automatic control", "D": "Local control"}}, {"qid": "T1E10", "answer": "B", "question": "Which of the following is an example of remote control as defined in Part 97?", "options": {"A": "Repeater operation", "B": "Operating the station over the Internet", "C": "Controlling a model aircraft, boat or car by amateur radio", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T1E11", "answer": "D", "question": "Who does the FCC presume to be the control operator of an amateur station, unless documentation to the contrary is in the station records?", "options": {"A": "The station custodian", "B": "The third party participant", "C": "The person operating the station equipment", "D": "The station licensee"}}, {"qid": "T1E12", "answer": "A", "question": "When, under normal circumstances, may a Technician Class licensee be the control operator of a station operating in an exclusive Extra Class operator segment of the amateur bands?", "options": {"A": "At no time", "B": "When operating a special event station", "C": "As part of a multi-operator contest team", "D": "When using a club station whose trustee is an Extra Class operator licensee"}}, {"qid": "T1F01", "answer": "A", "question": "What type of identification is being used when identifying a station on the air as Race Headquarters?", "options": {"A": "Tactical call sign", "B": "An official call sign reserved for RACES drills", "C": "SSID", "D": "Broadcast station"}}, {"qid": "T1F02", "answer": "C", "question": "When using tactical identifiers such as \ufffdRace Headquarters\ufffd during a community service net operation, how often must your station transmit the station\ufffds FCC-assigned call sign?", "options": {"A": "Never, the tactical call is sufficient", "B": "Once during every hour", "C": "At the end of each communication and every ten minutes during a communication", "D": "At the end of every transmission"}}, {"qid": "T1F03", "answer": "D", "question": "When is an amateur station required to transmit its assigned call sign?", "options": {"A": "At the beginning of each contact, and every 10 minutes thereafter", "B": "At least once during each transmission", "C": "At least every 15 minutes during and at the end of a communication", "D": "At least every 10 minutes during and at the end of a communication"}}, {"qid": "T1F04", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following is an acceptable language to use for station identification when operating in a phone sub-band?", "options": {"A": "Any language recognized by the United Nations", "B": "Any language recognized by the ITU", "C": "The English language", "D": "English, French, or Spanish"}}, {"qid": "T1F05", "answer": "B", "question": "What method of call sign identification is required for a station transmitting phone signals?", "options": {"A": "Send the call sign followed by the indicator RPT", "B": "Send the call sign using CW or phone emission", "C": "Send the call sign followed by the indicator R", "D": "Send the call sign using only phone emission"}}, {"qid": "T1F06", "answer": "D", "question": "Which of the following formats of a self-assigned indicator is acceptable when identifying using a phone transmission?", "options": {"A": "KL7CC stroke W3", "B": "KL7CC slant W3", "C": "KL7CC slash W3", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T1F07", "answer": "B", "question": "Which of the following restrictions apply when a non-licensed person is allowed to speak to a foreign station using a station under the control of a Technician Class control operator?", "options": {"A": "The person must be a U.S. citizen", "B": "The foreign station must be one with which the U.S. has a third party agreement", "C": "The licensed control operator must do the station identification", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T1F08", "answer": "D", "question": "Which indicator is required by the FCC to be transmitted after a station call sign?", "options": {"A": "/M when operating mobile", "B": "/R when operating a repeater", "C": "/ followed the FCC Region number when operating out of the region in which the license was issued", "D": "/KT, /AE or /AG when using new license privileges earned by CSCE while waiting for an upgrade to a previously issued license to appear in the FCC license database"}}, {"qid": "T1F09", "answer": "C", "question": "What type of amateur station simultaneously retransmits the signal of another amateur station on a different channel or channels?", "options": {"A": "Beacon station", "B": "Earth station", "C": "Repeater station", "D": "Message forwarding station"}}, {"qid": "T1F10", "answer": "A", "question": "Who is accountable should a repeater inadvertently retransmit communications that violate the FCC rules?", "options": {"A": "The control operator of the originating station", "B": "The control operator of the repeater", "C": "The owner of the repeater", "D": "Both the originating station and the repeater owner"}}, {"qid": "T1F11", "answer": "A", "question": "To which foreign stations do the FCC rules authorize the transmission of non-emergency third party communications?", "options": {"A": "Any station whose government permits such communications", "B": "Those in ITU Region 2 only", "C": "Those in ITU Regions 2 and 3 only", "D": "Those in ITU Region 3 only"}}, {"qid": "T1F12", "answer": "B", "question": "How many persons are required to be members of a club for a club station license to be issued by the FCC?", "options": {"A": "At least 5", "B": "At least 4", "C": "A trustee and 2 officers", "D": "At least 2"}}, {"qid": "T1F13", "answer": "B", "question": "When must the station licensee make the station and its records available for FCC inspection?", "options": {"A": "At any time ten days after notification by the FCC of such an inspection", "B": "At any time upon request by an FCC representative", "C": "Only after failing to comply with an FCC notice of violation", "D": "Only when presented with a valid warrant by an FCC official or government agent"}}, {"qid": "T2A01", "answer": "B", "question": "What is the most common repeater frequency offset in the 2 meter band?", "options": {"A": "Plus 500 kHz", "B": "Plus or minus 600 kHz", "C": "Minus 500 kHz", "D": "Only plus 600 kHz"}}, {"qid": "T2A02", "answer": "D", "question": "What is the national calling frequency for FM simplex operations in the 70 cm band?", "options": {"A": "146.520 MHz", "B": "145.000 MHz", "C": "432.100 MHz", "D": "446.000 MHz"}}, {"qid": "T2A03", "answer": "A", "question": "What is a common repeater frequency offset in the 70 cm band?", "options": {"A": "Plus or minus 5 MHz", "B": "Plus or minus 600 kHz", "C": "Minus 600 kHz", "D": "Plus 600 kHz"}}, {"qid": "T2A04", "answer": "B", "question": "What is an appropriate way to call another station on a repeater if you know the other station's call sign?", "options": {"A": "Say break, break then say the station's call sign", "B": "Say the station's call sign then identify with your call sign", "C": "Say CQ three times then the other station's call sign", "D": "Wait for the station to call CQ then answer it"}}, {"qid": "T2A05", "answer": "C", "question": "How should you respond to a station calling CQ?", "options": {"A": "Transmit CQ followed by the other station\ufffds call sign", "B": "Transmit your call sign followed by the other station\ufffds call sign", "C": "Transmit the other station\ufffds call sign followed by your call sign", "D": "Transmit a signal report followed by your call sign"}}, {"qid": "T2A06", "answer": "A", "question": "What must an amateur operator do when making on-air transmissions to test equipment or antennas?", "options": {"A": "Properly identify the transmitting station", "B": "Make test transmissions only after 10:00 p.m. local time", "C": "Notify the FCC of the test transmission", "D": "State the purpose of the test during the test procedure"}}, {"qid": "T2A07", "answer": "D", "question": "Which of the following is true when making a test transmission?", "options": {"A": "Station identification is not required if the transmission is less than 15 seconds", "B": "Station identification is not required if the transmission is less than 1 watt", "C": "Station identification is only required once an hour when the transmissions are for test purposes only", "D": "Station identification is required at least every ten minutes during the test and at the end of the test"}}, {"qid": "T2A08", "answer": "D", "question": "What is the meaning of the procedural signal \ufffdCQ\ufffd?", "options": {"A": "Call on the quarter hour", "B": "A new antenna is being tested (no station should answer)", "C": "Only the called station should transmit", "D": "Calling any station"}}, {"qid": "T2A09", "answer": "B", "question": "What brief statement is often transmitted in place of \ufffdCQ\ufffd to indicate that you are listening on a repeater?", "options": {"A": "The words \ufffdHello test\ufffd followed by your call sign", "B": "Your call sign", "C": "The repeater call sign followed by your call sign", "D": "The letters \ufffdQSY\ufffd followed by your call sign"}}, {"qid": "T2A10", "answer": "A", "question": "What is a band plan, beyond the privileges established by the FCC?", "options": {"A": "A voluntary guideline for using different modes or activities within an amateur band", "B": "A mandated list of operating schedules", "C": "A list of scheduled net frequencies", "D": "A plan devised by a club to indicate frequency band usage"}}, {"qid": "T2A11", "answer": "D", "question": "Which of the following is an FCC rule regarding power levels used in the amateur bands, under normal, non-distress circumstances?", "options": {"A": "There is no limit to power as long as there is no interference with other services", "B": "No more than 200 watts PEP may be used", "C": "Up to 1500 watts PEP may be used on any amateur frequency without restriction", "D": "While not exceeding the maximum power permitted on a given band, use the minimum power necessary to carry out the desired communication"}}, {"qid": "T2A12", "answer": "D", "question": "Which of the following is a guideline to use when choosing an operating frequency for calling CQ?", "options": {"A": "Listen first to be sure that no one else is using the frequency", "B": "Ask if the frequency is in use", "C": "Make sure you are in your assigned band", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T2B01", "answer": "C", "question": "What is the term used to describe an amateur station that is transmitting and receiving on the same frequency?", "options": {"A": "Full duplex communication", "B": "Diplex communication", "C": "Simplex communication", "D": "Multiplex communication"}}, {"qid": "T2B02", "answer": "D", "question": "What is the term used to describe the use of a sub-audible tone transmitted with normal voice audio to open the squelch of a receiver?", "options": {"A": "Carrier squelch", "B": "Tone burst", "C": "DTMF", "D": "CTCSS"}}, {"qid": "T2B03", "answer": "B", "question": "Which of the following describes the muting of receiver audio controlled solely by the presence or absence of an RF signal?", "options": {"A": "Tone squelch", "B": "Carrier squelch", "C": "CTCSS", "D": "Modulated carrier"}}, {"qid": "T2B04", "answer": "D", "question": "Which of the following common problems might cause you to be able to hear but not access a repeater even when transmitting with the proper offset?", "options": {"A": "The repeater receiver may require an audio tone burst for access", "B": "The repeater receiver may require a CTCSS tone for access", "C": "The repeater receiver may require a DCS tone sequence for access", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T2B05", "answer": "C", "question": "What determines the amount of deviation of an FM (as opposed to PM) signal?", "options": {"A": "Both the frequency and amplitude of the modulating signal", "B": "The frequency of the modulating signal", "C": "The amplitude of the modulating signal", "D": "The relative phase of the modulating signal and the carrier"}}, {"qid": "T2B06", "answer": "A", "question": "What happens when the deviation of an FM transmitter is increased?", "options": {"A": "Its signal occupies more bandwidth", "B": "Its output power increases", "C": "Its output power and bandwidth increases", "D": "Asymmetric modulation occurs"}}, {"qid": "T2B07", "answer": "A", "question": "What could cause your FM signal to interfere with stations on nearby frequencies?", "options": {"A": "Microphone gain too high, causing over-deviation", "B": "SWR too high", "C": "Incorrect CTCSS Tone", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T2B08", "answer": "A", "question": "Which of the following applies when two stations transmitting on the same frequency interfere with each other?", "options": {"A": "Common courtesy should prevail, but no one has absolute right to an amateur frequency", "B": "Whoever has the strongest signal has priority on the frequency", "C": "Whoever has been on the frequency the longest has priority on the frequency", "D": "The station which has the weakest signal has priority on the frequency"}}, {"qid": "T2B09", "answer": "A", "question": "Which of the following methods is encouraged by the FCC when identifying your station when using phone?", "options": {"A": "Use of a phonetic alphabet", "B": "Send your call sign in CW as well as voice", "C": "Repeat your call sign three times", "D": "Increase your signal to full power when identifying"}}, {"qid": "T2B10", "answer": "A", "question": "Which Q signal indicates that you are receiving interference from other stations?", "options": {"A": "QRM", "B": "QRN", "C": "QTH", "D": "QSB"}}, {"qid": "T2B11", "answer": "B", "question": "Which Q signal indicates that you are changing frequency?", "options": {"A": "QRU", "B": "QSY", "C": "QSL", "D": "QRZ"}}, {"qid": "T2B12", "answer": "A", "question": "Under what circumstances should you consider communicating via simplex rather than a repeater?", "options": {"A": "When the stations can communicate directly without using a repeater", "B": "Only when you have an endorsement for simplex operation on your license", "C": "Only when third party traffic is not being passed", "D": "Only if you have simplex modulation capability"}}, {"qid": "T2B13", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following is true of the use of SSB phone in amateur bands above 50 MHz?", "options": {"A": "It is permitted only by holders of a General Class or higher license", "B": "It is permitted only on repeaters", "C": "It is permitted in at least some portion of all the amateur bands above 50 MHz", "D": "It is permitted only on when power is limited to no more than 100 watts"}}, {"qid": "T2C01", "answer": "D", "question": "When do the FCC rules NOT apply to the operation of an amateur station?", "options": {"A": "When operating a RACES station", "B": "When operating under special FEMA rules", "C": "When operating under special ARES rules", "D": "Never, FCC rules always apply"}}, {"qid": "T2C02", "answer": "C", "question": "What is one way to recharge a 12-volt lead-acid station battery if the commercial power is out?", "options": {"A": "Cool the battery in ice for several hours", "B": "Add acid to the battery", "C": "Connect the battery in parallel with a vehicle\ufffds battery and run the engine", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T2C03", "answer": "C", "question": "What should be done to insure that voice message traffic containing proper names and unusual words are copied correctly by the receiving station?", "options": {"A": "The entire message should be repeated at least four times", "B": "Such messages must be limited to no more than 10 words", "C": "Such words and terms should be spelled out using a standard phonetic alphabet", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T2C04", "answer": "D", "question": "What do RACES and ARES have in common?", "options": {"A": "They represent the two largest ham clubs in the United States", "B": "Both organizations broadcast road and weather information", "C": "Neither may handle emergency traffic supporting public service agencies", "D": "Both organizations may provide communications during emergencies"}}, {"qid": "T2C05", "answer": "D", "question": "Which of the following describes the Radio Amateur Civil Emergency Service (RACES)?", "options": {"A": "A radio service using amateur frequencies for emergency management or civil defense communications", "B": "A radio service using amateur stations for emergency management or civil defense communications", "C": "An emergency service using amateur operators certified by a civil defense organization as being enrolled in that organization", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T2C06", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following is an accepted practice to get the immediate attention of a net control station when reporting an emergency?", "options": {"A": "Repeat the words SOS three times followed by the call sign of the reporting station", "B": "Press the push-to-talk button three times", "C": "Begin your transmission by saying \"Priority\" or \"Emergency\" followed by your call sign", "D": "Play a pre-recorded emergency alert tone followed by your call sign"}}, {"qid": "T2C07", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following is an accepted practice for an amateur operator who has checked into an emergency traffic net?", "options": {"A": "Provided that the frequency is quiet, announce the station call sign and location every 5 minutes", "B": "Move 5 kHz away from the net's frequency and use high power to ask other hams to keep clear of the net frequency", "C": "Remain on frequency without transmitting until asked to do so by the net control station", "D": "All of the choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T2C08", "answer": "A", "question": "Which of the following is a characteristic of good emergency traffic handling?", "options": {"A": "Passing messages exactly as received", "B": "Making decisions as to whether or not messages should be relayed or delivered", "C": "Communicating messages to the news media for broadcast outside the disaster area", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T2C09", "answer": "D", "question": "Are amateur station control operators ever permitted to operate outside the frequency privileges of their license class?", "options": {"A": "No", "B": "Yes, but only when part of a FEMA emergency plan", "C": "Yes, but only when part of a RACES emergency plan", "D": "Yes, but only if necessary in situations involving the immediate safety of human life or protection of property"}}, {"qid": "T2C10", "answer": "D", "question": "What is the preamble in a formal traffic message?", "options": {"A": "The first paragraph of the message text", "B": "The message number", "C": "The priority handling indicator for the message", "D": "The information needed to track the message as it passes through the amateur radio traffic handling system"}}, {"qid": "T2C11", "answer": "A", "question": "What is meant by the term \ufffdcheck\ufffd in reference to a formal traffic message?", "options": {"A": "The check is a count of the number of words or word equivalents in the text portion of the message", "B": "The check is the value of a money order attached to the message", "C": "The check is a list of stations that have relayed the message", "D": "The check is a box on the message form that tells you the message was received"}}, {"qid": "T2C12", "answer": "A", "question": "What is the Amateur Radio Emergency Service (ARES)?", "options": {"A": "Licensed amateurs who have voluntarily registered their qualifications and equipment for communications duty in the public service", "B": "Licensed amateurs who are members of the military and who voluntarily agreed to provide message handling services in the case of an emergency", "C": "A training program that provides licensing courses for those interested in obtaining an amateur license to use during emergencies", "D": "A training program that certifies amateur operators for membership in the Radio Amateur Civil Emergency Service"}}, {"qid": "T3A01", "answer": "D", "question": "What should you do if another operator reports that your station\ufffds 2 meter signals were strong just a moment ago, but now they are weak or distorted?", "options": {"A": "Change the batteries in your radio to a different type", "B": "Turn on the CTCSS tone", "C": "Ask the other operator to adjust his squelch control", "D": "Try moving a few feet or changing the direction of your antenna if possible, as reflections may be causing multi-path distortion"}}, {"qid": "T3A02", "answer": "B", "question": "Why are UHF signals often more effective from inside buildings than VHF signals?", "options": {"A": "VHF signals lose power faster over distance", "B": "The shorter wavelength allows them to more easily penetrate the structure of buildings", "C": "This is incorrect; VHF works better than UHF inside buildings", "D": "UHF antennas are more efficient than VHF antennas"}}, {"qid": "T3A03", "answer": "C", "question": "What antenna polarization is normally used for long-distance weak-signal CW and SSB contacts using the VHF and UHF bands?", "options": {"A": "Right-hand circular", "B": "Left-hand circular", "C": "Horizontal", "D": "Vertical"}}, {"qid": "T3A04", "answer": "B", "question": "What can happen if the antennas at opposite ends of a VHF or UHF line of sight radio link are not using the same polarization?", "options": {"A": "The modulation sidebands might become inverted", "B": "Signals could be significantly weaker", "C": "Signals have an echo effect on voices", "D": "Nothing significant will happen"}}, {"qid": "T3A05", "answer": "B", "question": "When using a directional antenna, how might your station be able to access a distant repeater if buildings or obstructions are blocking the direct line of sight path?", "options": {"A": "Change from vertical to horizontal polarization", "B": "Try to find a path that reflects signals to the repeater", "C": "Try the long path", "D": "Increase the antenna SWR"}}, {"qid": "T3A06", "answer": "B", "question": "What term is commonly used to describe the rapid fluttering sound sometimes heard from mobile stations that are moving while transmitting?", "options": {"A": "Flip-flopping", "B": "Picket fencing", "C": "Frequency shifting", "D": "Pulsing"}}, {"qid": "T3A07", "answer": "A", "question": "What type of wave carries radio signals between transmitting and receiving stations?", "options": {"A": "Electromagnetic", "B": "Electrostatic", "C": "Surface acoustic", "D": "Magnetostrictive"}}, {"qid": "T3A08", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following is a likely cause of irregular fading of signals received by ionospheric reflection?", "options": {"A": "Frequency shift due to Faraday rotation", "B": "Interference from thunderstorms", "C": "Random combining of signals arriving via different paths", "D": "Intermodulation distortion"}}, {"qid": "T3A09", "answer": "B", "question": "Which of the following results from the fact that skip signals refracted from the ionosphere are elliptically polarized?", "options": {"A": "Digital modes are unusable", "B": "Either vertically or horizontally polarized antennas may be used for transmission or reception", "C": "FM voice is unusable", "D": "Both the transmitting and receiving antennas must be of the same polarization"}}, {"qid": "T3A10", "answer": "D", "question": "What may occur if data signals propagate over multiple paths?", "options": {"A": "Transmission rates can be increased by a factor equal to the number of separate paths observed", "B": "Transmission rates must be decreased by a factor equal to the number of separate paths observed", "C": "No significant changes will occur if the signals are transmitting using FM", "D": "Error rates are likely to increase"}}, {"qid": "T3A11", "answer": "C", "question": "Which part of the atmosphere enables the propagation of radio signals around the world?", "options": {"A": "The stratosphere", "B": "The troposphere", "C": "The ionosphere", "D": "The magnetosphere"}}, {"qid": "T3B01", "answer": "C", "question": "What is the name for the distance a radio wave travels during one complete cycle?", "options": {"A": "Wave speed", "B": "Waveform", "C": "Wavelength", "D": "Wave spread"}}, {"qid": "T3B02", "answer": "A", "question": "What property of a radio wave is used to describe its polarization?", "options": {"A": "The orientation of the electric field", "B": "The orientation of the magnetic field", "C": "The ratio of the energy in the magnetic field to the energy in the electric field", "D": "The ratio of the velocity to the wavelength"}}, {"qid": "T3B03", "answer": "C", "question": "What are the two components of a radio wave?", "options": {"A": "AC and DC", "B": "Voltage and current", "C": "Electric and magnetic fields", "D": "Ionizing and non-ionizing radiation"}}, {"qid": "T3B04", "answer": "A", "question": "How fast does a radio wave travel through free space?", "options": {"A": "At the speed of light", "B": "At the speed of sound", "C": "Its speed is inversely proportional to its wavelength", "D": "Its speed increases as the frequency increases"}}, {"qid": "T3B05", "answer": "B", "question": "How does the wavelength of a radio wave relate to its frequency?", "options": {"A": "The wavelength gets longer as the frequency increases", "B": "The wavelength gets shorter as the frequency increases", "C": "There is no relationship between wavelength and frequency", "D": "The wavelength depends on the bandwidth of the signal"}}, {"qid": "T3B06", "answer": "D", "question": "What is the formula for converting frequency to approximate wavelength in meters?", "options": {"A": "Wavelength in meters equals frequency in hertz multiplied by 300", "B": "Wavelength in meters equals frequency in hertz divided by 300", "C": "Wavelength in meters equals frequency in megahertz divided by 300", "D": "Wavelength in meters equals 300 divided by frequency in megahertz"}}, {"qid": "T3B07", "answer": "A", "question": "What property of radio waves is often used to identify the different frequency bands?", "options": {"A": "The approximate wavelength", "B": "The magnetic intensity of waves", "C": "The time it takes for waves to travel one mile", "D": "The voltage standing wave ratio of waves"}}, {"qid": "T3B08", "answer": "B", "question": "What are the frequency limits of the VHF spectrum?", "options": {"A": "30 to 300 kHz", "B": "30 to 300 MHz", "C": "300 to 3000 kHz", "D": "300 to 3000 MHz"}}, {"qid": "T3B09", "answer": "D", "question": "What are the frequency limits of the UHF spectrum?", "options": {"A": "30 to 300 kHz", "B": "30 to 300 MHz", "C": "300 to 3000 kHz", "D": "300 to 3000 MHz"}}, {"qid": "T3B10", "answer": "C", "question": "What frequency range is referred to as HF?", "options": {"A": "300 to 3000 MHz", "B": "30 to 300 MHz", "C": "3 to 30 MHz", "D": "300 to 3000 kHz"}}, {"qid": "T3B11", "answer": "B", "question": "What is the approximate velocity of a radio wave as it travels through free space?", "options": {"A": "3000 kilometers per second", "B": "300,000,000 meters per second", "C": "300,000 miles per hour", "D": "186,000 miles per hour"}}, {"qid": "T3C01", "answer": "C", "question": "Why are direct (not via a repeater) UHF signals rarely heard from stations outside your local coverage area?", "options": {"A": "They are too weak to go very far", "B": "FCC regulations prohibit them from going more than 50 miles", "C": "UHF signals are usually not reflected by the ionosphere", "D": "They collide with trees and shrubbery and fade out"}}, {"qid": "T3C02", "answer": "D", "question": "Which of the following might be happening when VHF signals are being received from long distances?", "options": {"A": "Signals are being reflected from outer space", "B": "Signals are arriving by sub-surface ducting", "C": "Signals are being reflected by lightning storms in your area", "D": "Signals are being refracted from a sporadic E layer"}}, {"qid": "T3C03", "answer": "B", "question": "What is a characteristic of VHF signals received via auroral reflection?", "options": {"A": "Signals from distances of 10,000 or more miles are common", "B": "The signals exhibit rapid fluctuations of strength and often sound distorted", "C": "These types of signals occur only during winter nighttime hours", "D": "These types of signals are generally strongest when your antenna is aimed west"}}, {"qid": "T3C04", "answer": "B", "question": "Which of the following propagation types is most commonly associated with occasional strong over-the-horizon signals on the 10, 6, and 2 meter bands?", "options": {"A": "Backscatter", "B": "Sporadic E", "C": "D layer absorption", "D": "Gray-line propagation"}}, {"qid": "T3C05", "answer": "A", "question": "Which of the following effects might cause radio signals to be heard despite obstructions between the transmitting and receiving stations?", "options": {"A": "Knife-edge diffraction", "B": "Faraday rotation", "C": "Quantum tunneling", "D": "Doppler shift"}}, {"qid": "T3C06", "answer": "A", "question": "What mode is responsible for allowing over-the-horizon VHF and UHF communications to ranges of approximately 300 miles on a regular basis?", "options": {"A": "Tropospheric scatter", "B": "D layer refraction", "C": "F2 layer refraction", "D": "Faraday rotation"}}, {"qid": "T3C07", "answer": "B", "question": "What band is best suited for communicating via meteor scatter?", "options": {"A": "10 meters", "B": "6 meters", "C": "2 meters", "D": "70 cm"}}, {"qid": "T3C08", "answer": "D", "question": "What causes tropospheric ducting?", "options": {"A": "Discharges of lightning during electrical storms", "B": "Sunspots and solar flares", "C": "Updrafts from hurricanes and tornadoes", "D": "Temperature inversions in the atmosphere"}}, {"qid": "T3C09", "answer": "A", "question": "What is generally the best time for long-distance 10 meter band propagation via the F layer?", "options": {"A": "From dawn to shortly after sunset during periods of high sunspot activity", "B": "From shortly after sunset to dawn during periods of high sunspot activity", "C": "From dawn to shortly after sunset during periods of low sunspot activity", "D": "From shortly after sunset to dawn during periods of low sunspot activity"}}, {"qid": "T3C10", "answer": "A", "question": "What is the radio horizon?", "options": {"A": "The distance over which two stations can communicate by direct path", "B": "The distance from the ground to a horizontally mounted antenna", "C": "The farthest point you can see when standing at the base of your antenna tower", "D": "The shortest distance between two points on the Earth's surface"}}, {"qid": "T3C11", "answer": "C", "question": "Why do VHF and UHF radio signals usually travel somewhat farther than the visual line of sight distance between two stations?", "options": {"A": "Radio signals move somewhat faster than the speed of light", "B": "Radio waves are not blocked by dust particles", "C": "The Earth seems less curved to radio waves than to light", "D": "Radio waves are blocked by dust particles"}}, {"qid": "T3C12", "answer": "A", "question": "Which of the following bands may provide long distance communications during the peak of the sunspot cycle?", "options": {"A": "Six or ten meters", "B": "23 centimeters", "C": "70 centimeters or 1.25 meters", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T4A01", "answer": "B", "question": "Which of the following is true concerning the microphone connectors on amateur transceivers?", "options": {"A": "All transceivers use the same microphone connector type", "B": "Some connectors include push-to-talk and voltages for powering the microphone", "C": "All transceivers using the same connector type are wired identically", "D": "Un-keyed connectors allow any microphone to be connected"}}, {"qid": "T4A02", "answer": "D", "question": "How might a computer be used as part of an amateur radio station?", "options": {"A": "For logging contacts and contact information", "B": "For sending and/or receiving CW", "C": "For generating and decoding digital signals", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T4A03", "answer": "A", "question": "Which is a good reason to use a regulated power supply for communications equipment?", "options": {"A": "It prevents voltage fluctuations from reaching sensitive circuits", "B": "A regulated power supply has FCC approval", "C": "A fuse or circuit breaker regulates the power", "D": "Power consumption is independent of load"}}, {"qid": "T4A04", "answer": "A", "question": "Where must a filter be installed to reduce harmonic emissions from your station?", "options": {"A": "Between the transmitter and the antenna", "B": "Between the receiver and the transmitter", "C": "At the station power supply", "D": "At the microphone"}}, {"qid": "T4A05", "answer": "A", "question": "Where should an in-line SWR meter be connected to monitor the standing wave ratio of the station antenna system?", "options": {"A": "In series with the feed line, between the transmitter and antenna", "B": "In series with the station's ground", "C": "In parallel with the push-to-talk line and the antenna", "D": "In series with the power supply cable, as close as possible to the radio"}}, {"qid": "T4A06", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following would be connected between a transceiver and computer in a packet radio station?", "options": {"A": "Transmatch", "B": "Mixer", "C": "Terminal node controller", "D": "Antenna"}}, {"qid": "T4A07", "answer": "C", "question": "How is a computer\ufffds sound card used when conducting digital communications using a computer?", "options": {"A": "The sound card communicates between the computer CPU and the video display", "B": "The sound card records the audio frequency for video display", "C": "The sound card provides audio to the microphone input and converts received audio to digital form", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T4A08", "answer": "D", "question": "Which type of conductor is best to use for RF grounding?", "options": {"A": "Round stranded wire", "B": "Round copper-clad steel wire", "C": "Twisted-pair cable", "D": "Flat strap"}}, {"qid": "T4A09", "answer": "D", "question": "Which of the following could you use to cure distorted audio caused by RF current flowing on the shield of a microphone cable?", "options": {"A": "Band-pass filter", "B": "Low-pass filter", "C": "Preamplifier", "D": "Ferrite choke"}}, {"qid": "T4A10", "answer": "B", "question": "What is the source of a high-pitched whine that varies with engine speed in a mobile transceiver\ufffds receive audio?", "options": {"A": "The ignition system", "B": "The alternator", "C": "The electric fuel pump", "D": "Anti-lock braking system controllers"}}, {"qid": "T4A11", "answer": "A", "question": "Where should the negative return connection of a mobile transceiver's power cable be connected?", "options": {"A": "At the battery or engine block ground strap", "B": "At the antenna mount", "C": "To any metal part of the vehicle", "D": "Through the transceiver\ufffds mounting bracket"}}, {"qid": "T4A12", "answer": "D", "question": "What could be happening if another operator reports a variable high-pitched whine on the audio from your mobile transmitter?", "options": {"A": "Your microphone is picking up noise from an open window", "B": "You have the volume on your receiver set too high", "C": "You need to adjust your squelch control", "D": "Noise on the vehicle\ufffds electrical system is being transmitted along with your speech audio"}}, {"qid": "T4B01", "answer": "B", "question": "What may happen if a transmitter is operated with the microphone gain set too high?", "options": {"A": "The output power might be too high", "B": "The output signal might become distorted", "C": "The frequency might vary", "D": "The SWR might increase"}}, {"qid": "T4B02", "answer": "A", "question": "Which of the following can be used to enter the operating frequency on a modern transceiver?", "options": {"A": "The keypad or VFO knob", "B": "The CTCSS or DTMF encoder", "C": "The Automatic Frequency Control", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T4B03", "answer": "D", "question": "What is the purpose of the squelch control on a transceiver?", "options": {"A": "To set the highest level of volume desired", "B": "To set the transmitter power level", "C": "To adjust the automatic gain control", "D": "To mute receiver output noise when no signal is being received"}}, {"qid": "T4B04", "answer": "B", "question": "What is a way to enable quick access to a favorite frequency on your transceiver?", "options": {"A": "Enable the CTCSS tones", "B": "Store the frequency in a memory channel", "C": "Disable the CTCSS tones", "D": "Use the scan mode to select the desired frequency"}}, {"qid": "T4B05", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following would reduce ignition interference to a receiver?", "options": {"A": "Change frequency slightly", "B": "Decrease the squelch setting", "C": "Turn on the noise blanker", "D": "Use the RIT control"}}, {"qid": "T4B06", "answer": "D", "question": "Which of the following controls could be used if the voice pitch of a single-sideband signal seems too high or low?", "options": {"A": "The AGC or limiter", "B": "The bandwidth selection", "C": "The tone squelch", "D": "The receiver RIT or clarifier"}}, {"qid": "T4B07", "answer": "B", "question": "What does the term \ufffdRIT\ufffd mean?", "options": {"A": "Receiver Input Tone", "B": "Receiver Incremental Tuning", "C": "Rectifier Inverter Test", "D": "Remote Input Transmitter"}}, {"qid": "T4B08", "answer": "B", "question": "What is the advantage of having multiple receive bandwidth choices on a multimode transceiver?", "options": {"A": "Permits monitoring several modes at once", "B": "Permits noise or interference reduction by selecting a bandwidth matching the mode", "C": "Increases the number of frequencies that can be stored in memory", "D": "Increases the amount of offset between receive and transmit frequencies"}}, {"qid": "T4B09", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following is an appropriate receive filter bandwidth to select in order to minimize noise and interference for SSB reception?", "options": {"A": "500 Hz", "B": "1000 Hz", "C": "2400 Hz", "D": "5000 Hz"}}, {"qid": "T4B10", "answer": "A", "question": "Which of the following is an appropriate receive filter bandwidth to select in order to minimize noise and interference for CW reception?", "options": {"A": "500 Hz", "B": "1000 Hz", "C": "2400 Hz", "D": "5000 Hz"}}, {"qid": "T4B11", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following describes the common meaning of the term \"repeater offset\"?", "options": {"A": "The distance between the repeater\ufffds transmit and receive antennas", "B": "The time delay before the repeater timer resets", "C": "The difference between the repeater\ufffds transmit and receive frequencies", "D": "Matching the antenna impedance to the feed line impedance"}}, {"qid": "T4B12", "answer": "A", "question": "What is the function of automatic gain control or AGC?", "options": {"A": "To keep received audio relatively constant", "B": "To protect an antenna from lightning", "C": "To eliminate RF on the station cabling", "D": "An asymmetric goniometer control used for antenna matching"}}, {"qid": "T5A01", "answer": "D", "question": "Electrical current is measured in which of the following units?", "options": {"A": "Volts", "B": "Watts", "C": "Ohms", "D": "Amperes"}}, {"qid": "T5A02", "answer": "B", "question": "Electrical power is measured in which of the following units?", "options": {"A": "Volts", "B": "Watts", "C": "Ohms", "D": "Amperes"}}, {"qid": "T5A03", "answer": "D", "question": "What is the name for the flow of electrons in an electric circuit?", "options": {"A": "Voltage", "B": "Resistance", "C": "Capacitance", "D": "Current"}}, {"qid": "T5A05", "answer": "A", "question": "What is the electrical term for the electromotive force (EMF) that causes electron flow?", "options": {"A": "Voltage", "B": "Ampere-hours", "C": "Capacitance", "D": "Inductance"}}, {"qid": "T5A06", "answer": "A", "question": "How much voltage does a mobile transceiver usually require?", "options": {"A": "About 12 volts", "B": "About 30 volts", "C": "About 120 volts", "D": "About 240 volts"}}, {"qid": "T5A07", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following is a good electrical conductor?", "options": {"A": "Glass", "B": "Wood", "C": "Copper", "D": "Rubber"}}, {"qid": "T5A08", "answer": "B", "question": "Which of the following is a good electrical insulator?", "options": {"A": "Copper", "B": "Glass", "C": "Aluminum", "D": "Mercury"}}, {"qid": "T5A09", "answer": "A", "question": "What is the name for a current that reverses direction on a regular basis?", "options": {"A": "Alternating current", "B": "Direct current", "C": "Circular current", "D": "Vertical current"}}, {"qid": "T5A10", "answer": "C", "question": "Which term describes the rate at which electrical energy is used?", "options": {"A": "Resistance", "B": "Current", "C": "Power", "D": "Voltage"}}, {"qid": "T5A11", "answer": "A", "question": "What is the basic unit of electromotive force?", "options": {"A": "The volt", "B": "The watt", "C": "The ampere", "D": "The ohm"}}, {"qid": "T5A12", "answer": "D", "question": "What term describes the number of times per second that an alternating current reverses direction?", "options": {"A": "Pulse rate", "B": "Speed", "C": "Wavelength", "D": "Frequency"}}, {"qid": "T5B01", "answer": "C", "question": "How many milliamperes is 1.5 amperes?", "options": {"A": "15 milliamperes", "B": "150 milliamperes", "C": "1,500 milliamperes", "D": "15,000 milliamperes"}}, {"qid": "T5B02", "answer": "A", "question": "What is another way to specify a radio signal frequency of 1,500,000 hertz?", "options": {"A": "1500 kHz", "B": "1500 MHz", "C": "15 GHz", "D": "150 kHz"}}, {"qid": "T5B03", "answer": "C", "question": "How many volts are equal to one kilovolt?", "options": {"A": "One one-thousandth of a volt", "B": "One hundred volts", "C": "One thousand volts", "D": "One million volts"}}, {"qid": "T5B04", "answer": "A", "question": "How many volts are equal to one microvolt?", "options": {"A": "One one-millionth of a volt", "B": "One million volts", "C": "One thousand kilovolts", "D": "One one-thousandth of a volt"}}, {"qid": "T5B05", "answer": "B", "question": "Which of the following is equivalent to 500 milliwatts?", "options": {"A": "0.02 watts", "B": "0.5 watts", "C": "5 watts", "D": "50 watts"}}, {"qid": "T5B06", "answer": "C", "question": "If an ammeter calibrated in amperes is used to measure a 3000-milliampere current, what reading would it show?", "options": {"A": "0.003 amperes", "B": "0.3 amperes", "C": "3 amperes", "D": "3,000,000 amperes"}}, {"qid": "T5B07", "answer": "C", "question": "If a frequency readout calibrated in megahertz shows a reading of 3.525 MHz, what would it show if it were calibrated in kilohertz?", "options": {"A": "0.003525 kHz", "B": "35.25 kHz", "C": "3525 kHz", "D": "3,525,000 kHz"}}, {"qid": "T5B08", "answer": "B", "question": "How many microfarads are 1,000,000 picofarads?", "options": {"A": "0.001 microfarads", "B": "1 microfarad", "C": "1000 microfarads", "D": "1,000,000,000 microfarads"}}, {"qid": "T5B09", "answer": "B", "question": "What is the approximate amount of change, measured in decibels (dB), of a power increase from 5 watts to 10 watts?", "options": {"A": "2 dB", "B": "3 dB", "C": "5 dB", "D": "10 dB"}}, {"qid": "T5B10", "answer": "C", "question": "What is the approximate amount of change, measured in decibels (dB), of a power decrease from 12 watts to 3 watts?", "options": {"A": "-1 dB", "B": "-3 dB", "C": "-6 dB", "D": "-9 dB"}}, {"qid": "T5B11", "answer": "A", "question": "What is the approximate amount of change, measured in decibels (dB), of a power increase from 20 watts to 200 watts?", "options": {"A": "10 dB", "B": "12 dB", "C": "18 dB", "D": "28 dB"}}, {"qid": "T5B12", "answer": "A", "question": "Which of the following frequencies is equal to 28,400 kHz?", "options": {"A": "28.400 MHz", "B": "2.800 MHz", "C": "284.00 MHz", "D": "28.400 kHz"}}, {"qid": "T5B13", "answer": "C", "question": "If a frequency readout shows a reading of 2425 MHz, what frequency is that in GHz?", "options": {"A": "0.002425 GHZ", "B": "24.25 GHz", "C": "2.425 GHz", "D": "2425 GHz"}}, {"qid": "T5C01", "answer": "D", "question": "What is the ability to store energy in an electric field called?", "options": {"A": "Inductance", "B": "Resistance", "C": "Tolerance", "D": "Capacitance"}}, {"qid": "T5C02", "answer": "A", "question": "What is the basic unit of capacitance?", "options": {"A": "The farad", "B": "The ohm", "C": "The volt", "D": "The henry"}}, {"qid": "T5C03", "answer": "D", "question": "What is the ability to store energy in a magnetic field called?", "options": {"A": "Admittance", "B": "Capacitance", "C": "Resistance", "D": "Inductance"}}, {"qid": "T5C04", "answer": "C", "question": "What is the basic unit of inductance?", "options": {"A": "The coulomb", "B": "The farad", "C": "The henry", "D": "The ohm"}}, {"qid": "T5C05", "answer": "A", "question": "What is the unit of frequency?", "options": {"A": "Hertz", "B": "Henry", "C": "Farad", "D": "Tesla"}}, {"qid": "T5C06", "answer": "A", "question": "What does the abbreviation \ufffdRF\ufffd refer to?", "options": {"A": "Radio frequency signals of all types", "B": "The resonant frequency of a tuned circuit", "C": "The real frequency transmitted as opposed to the apparent frequency", "D": "Reflective force in antenna transmission lines"}}, {"qid": "T5C07", "answer": "C", "question": "What is a usual name for electromagnetic waves that travel through space?", "options": {"A": "Gravity waves", "B": "Sound waves", "C": "Radio waves", "D": "Pressure waves"}}, {"qid": "T5C08", "answer": "A", "question": "What is the formula used to calculate electrical power in a DC circuit?", "options": {"A": "Power (P) equals voltage (E) multiplied by current (I)", "B": "Power (P) equals voltage (E) divided by current (I)", "C": "Power (P) equals voltage (E) minus current (I)", "D": "Power (P) equals voltage (E) plus current (I)"}}, {"qid": "T5C09", "answer": "A", "question": "How much power is being used in a circuit when the applied voltage is 13.8 volts DC and the current is 10 amperes?", "options": {"A": "138 watts", "B": "0.7 watts", "C": "23.8 watts", "D": "3.8 watts"}}, {"qid": "T5C10", "answer": "B", "question": "How much power is being used in a circuit when the applied voltage is 12 volts DC and the current is 2.5 amperes?", "options": {"A": "4.8 watts", "B": "30 watts", "C": "14.5 watts", "D": "0.208 watts"}}, {"qid": "T5C11", "answer": "B", "question": "How many amperes are flowing in a circuit when the applied voltage is 12 volts DC and the load is 120 watts?", "options": {"A": "0.1 amperes", "B": "10 amperes", "C": "12 amperes", "D": "132 amperes"}}, {"qid": "T5C12", "answer": "A", "question": "What is meant by the term impedance?", "options": {"A": "It is a measure of the opposition to AC current flow in a circuit", "B": "It is the inverse of resistance", "C": "It is a measure of the Q or Quality Factor of a component", "D": "It is a measure of the power handling capability of a component"}}, {"qid": "T5C13", "answer": "D", "question": "What are the units of impedance?", "options": {"A": "Volts", "B": "Amperes", "C": "Coulombs", "D": "Ohms"}}, {"qid": "T5D01", "answer": "B", "question": "What formula is used to calculate current in a circuit?", "options": {"A": "Current (I) equals voltage (E) multiplied by resistance (R)", "B": "Current (I) equals voltage (E) divided by resistance (R)", "C": "Current (I) equals voltage (E) added to resistance (R)", "D": "Current (I) equals voltage (E) minus resistance (R)"}}, {"qid": "T5D02", "answer": "A", "question": "What formula is used to calculate voltage in a circuit?", "options": {"A": "Voltage (E) equals current (I) multiplied by resistance (R)", "B": "Voltage (E) equals current (I) divided by resistance (R)", "C": "Voltage (E) equals current (I) added to resistance (R)", "D": "Voltage (E) equals current (I) minus resistance (R)"}}, {"qid": "T5D03", "answer": "B", "question": "What formula is used to calculate resistance in a circuit?", "options": {"A": "Resistance (R) equals voltage (E) multiplied by current (I)", "B": "Resistance (R) equals voltage (E) divided by current (I)", "C": "Resistance (R) equals voltage (E) added to current (I)", "D": "Resistance (R) equals voltage (E) minus current (I)"}}, {"qid": "T5D04", "answer": "B", "question": "What is the resistance of a circuit in which a current of 3 amperes flows through a resistor connected to 90 volts?", "options": {"A": "3 ohms", "B": "30 ohms", "C": "93 ohms", "D": "270 ohms"}}, {"qid": "T5D05", "answer": "C", "question": "What is the resistance in a circuit for which the applied voltage is 12 volts and the current flow is 1.5 amperes?", "options": {"A": "18 ohms", "B": "0.125 ohms", "C": "8 ohms", "D": "13.5 ohms"}}, {"qid": "T5D06", "answer": "A", "question": "What is the resistance of a circuit that draws 4 amperes from a 12-volt source?", "options": {"A": "3 ohms", "B": "16 ohms", "C": "48 ohms", "D": "8 Ohms"}}, {"qid": "T5D07", "answer": "D", "question": "What is the current flow in a circuit with an applied voltage of 120 volts and a resistance of 80 ohms?", "options": {"A": "9600 amperes", "B": "200 amperes", "C": "0.667 amperes", "D": "1.5 amperes"}}, {"qid": "T5D08", "answer": "C", "question": "What is the current flowing through a 100-ohm resistor connected across 200 volts?", "options": {"A": "20,000 amperes", "B": "0.5 amperes", "C": "2 amperes", "D": "100 amperes"}}, {"qid": "T5D09", "answer": "C", "question": "What is the current flowing through a 24-ohm resistor connected across 240 volts?", "options": {"A": "24,000 amperes", "B": "0.1 amperes", "C": "10 amperes", "D": "216 amperes"}}, {"qid": "T5D10", "answer": "A", "question": "What is the voltage across a 2-ohm resistor if a current of 0.5 amperes flows through it?", "options": {"A": "1 volt", "B": "0.25 volts", "C": "2.5 volts", "D": "1.5 volts"}}, {"qid": "T5D11", "answer": "B", "question": "What is the voltage across a 10-ohm resistor if a current of 1 ampere flows through it?", "options": {"A": "1 volt", "B": "10 volts", "C": "11 volts", "D": "9 volts"}}, {"qid": "T5D12", "answer": "D", "question": "What is the voltage across a 10-ohm resistor if a current of 2 amperes flows through it?", "options": {"A": "8 volts", "B": "0.2 volts", "C": "12 volts", "D": "20 volts"}}, {"qid": "T6A01", "answer": "B", "question": "What electrical component is used to oppose the flow of current in a DC circuit?", "options": {"A": "Inductor", "B": "Resistor", "C": "Voltmeter", "D": "Transformer"}}, {"qid": "T6A02", "answer": "C", "question": "What type of component is often used as an adjustable volume control?", "options": {"A": "Fixed resistor", "B": "Power resistor", "C": "Potentiometer", "D": "Transformer"}}, {"qid": "T6A03", "answer": "B", "question": "What electrical parameter is controlled by a potentiometer?", "options": {"A": "Inductance", "B": "Resistance", "C": "Capacitance", "D": "Field strength"}}, {"qid": "T6A04", "answer": "B", "question": "What electrical component stores energy in an electric field?", "options": {"A": "Resistor", "B": "Capacitor", "C": "Inductor", "D": "Diode"}}, {"qid": "T6A05", "answer": "D", "question": "What type of electrical component consists of two or more conductive surfaces separated by an insulator?", "options": {"A": "Resistor", "B": "Potentiometer", "C": "Oscillator", "D": "Capacitor"}}, {"qid": "T6A06", "answer": "C", "question": "What type of electrical component stores energy in a magnetic field?", "options": {"A": "Resistor", "B": "Capacitor", "C": "Inductor", "D": "Diode"}}, {"qid": "T6A07", "answer": "D", "question": "What electrical component is usually composed of a coil of wire?", "options": {"A": "Switch", "B": "Capacitor", "C": "Diode", "D": "Inductor"}}, {"qid": "T6A08", "answer": "B", "question": "What electrical component is used to connect or disconnect electrical circuits?", "options": {"A": "Magnetron", "B": "Switch", "C": "Thermistor", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T6A09", "answer": "A", "question": "What electrical component is used to protect other circuit components from current overloads?", "options": {"A": "Fuse", "B": "Capacitor", "C": "Inductor", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T6A10", "answer": "D", "question": "Which of the following battery types is rechargeable?", "options": {"A": "Nickel-metal hydride", "B": "Lithium-ion", "C": "Lead-acid gel-cell", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T6A11", "answer": "B", "question": "Which of the following battery types is not rechargeable?", "options": {"A": "Nickel-cadmium", "B": "Carbon-zinc", "C": "Lead-acid", "D": "Lithium-ion"}}, {"qid": "T6B01", "answer": "D", "question": "What class of electronic components is capable of using a voltage or current signal to control current flow?", "options": {"A": "Capacitors", "B": "Inductors", "C": "Resistors", "D": "Transistors"}}, {"qid": "T6B02", "answer": "C", "question": "What electronic component allows current to flow in only one direction?", "options": {"A": "Resistor", "B": "Fuse", "C": "Diode", "D": "Driven Element"}}, {"qid": "T6B03", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of these components can be used as an electronic switch or amplifier?", "options": {"A": "Oscillator", "B": "Potentiometer", "C": "Transistor", "D": "Voltmeter"}}, {"qid": "T6B04", "answer": "B", "question": "Which of the following components can be made of three layers of semiconductor material?", "options": {"A": "Alternator", "B": "Transistor", "C": "Triode", "D": "Pentagrid converter"}}, {"qid": "T6B05", "answer": "A", "question": "Which of the following electronic components can amplify signals?", "options": {"A": "Transistor", "B": "Variable resistor", "C": "Electrolytic capacitor", "D": "Multi-cell battery"}}, {"qid": "T6B06", "answer": "B", "question": "How is the cathode lead of a semiconductor diode usually identified?", "options": {"A": "With the word cathode", "B": "With a stripe", "C": "With the letter C", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T6B07", "answer": "B", "question": "What does the abbreviation LED stand for?", "options": {"A": "Low Emission Diode", "B": "Light Emitting Diode", "C": "Liquid Emission Detector", "D": "Long Echo Delay"}}, {"qid": "T6B08", "answer": "A", "question": "What does the abbreviation FET stand for?", "options": {"A": "Field Effect Transistor", "B": "Fast Electron Transistor", "C": "Free Electron Transition", "D": "Field Emission Thickness"}}, {"qid": "T6B09", "answer": "C", "question": "What are the names of the two electrodes of a diode?", "options": {"A": "Plus and minus", "B": "Source and drain", "C": "Anode and cathode", "D": "Gate and base"}}, {"qid": "T6B10", "answer": "A", "question": "What are the three electrodes of a PNP or NPN transistor?", "options": {"A": "Emitter, base, and collector", "B": "Source, gate, and drain", "C": "Cathode, grid, and plate", "D": "Cathode, drift cavity, and collector"}}, {"qid": "T6B11", "answer": "B", "question": "What at are the three electrodes of a field effect transistor?", "options": {"A": "Emitter, base, and collector", "B": "Source, gate, and drain", "C": "Cathode, grid, and plate", "D": "Cathode, gate, and anode"}}, {"qid": "T6B12", "answer": "A", "question": "What is the term that describes a transistor's ability to amplify a signal?", "options": {"A": "Gain", "B": "Forward resistance", "C": "Forward voltage drop", "D": "On resistance"}}, {"qid": "T6C01", "answer": "C", "question": "What is the name for standardized representations of components in an electrical wiring diagram?", "options": {"A": "Electrical depictions", "B": "Grey sketch", "C": "Schematic symbols", "D": "Component callouts"}}, {"qid": "T6C02", "answer": "A", "question": "What is component 1 in figure T1?", "options": {"A": "Resistor", "B": "Transistor", "C": "Battery", "D": "Connector"}}, {"qid": "T6C03", "answer": "B", "question": "What is component 2 in figure T1?", "options": {"A": "Resistor", "B": "Transistor", "C": "Indicator lamp", "D": "Connector"}}, {"qid": "T6C04", "answer": "C", "question": "What is component 3 in figure T1?", "options": {"A": "Resistor", "B": "Transistor", "C": "Lamp", "D": "Ground symbol"}}, {"qid": "T6C05", "answer": "C", "question": "What is component 4 in figure T1?", "options": {"A": "Resistor", "B": "Transistor", "C": "Battery", "D": "Ground symbol"}}, {"qid": "T6C06", "answer": "B", "question": "What is component 6 in figure T2?", "options": {"A": "Resistor", "B": "Capacitor", "C": "Regulator IC", "D": "Transistor"}}, {"qid": "T6C07", "answer": "D", "question": "What is component 8 in figure T2?", "options": {"A": "Resistor", "B": "Inductor", "C": "Regulator IC", "D": "Light emitting diode"}}, {"qid": "T6C08", "answer": "C", "question": "What is component 9 in figure T2?", "options": {"A": "Variable capacitor", "B": "Variable inductor", "C": "Variable resistor", "D": "Variable transformer"}}, {"qid": "T6C09", "answer": "D", "question": "What is component 4 in figure T2?", "options": {"A": "Variable inductor", "B": "Double-pole switch", "C": "Potentiometer", "D": "Transformer"}}, {"qid": "T6C10", "answer": "D", "question": "What is component 3 in figure T3?", "options": {"A": "Connector", "B": "Meter", "C": "Variable capacitor", "D": "Variable inductor"}}, {"qid": "T6C11", "answer": "A", "question": "What is component 4 in figure T3?", "options": {"A": "Antenna", "B": "Transmitter", "C": "Dummy load", "D": "Ground"}}, {"qid": "T6C12", "answer": "A", "question": "What do the symbols on an electrical circuit schematic diagram represent?", "options": {"A": "Electrical components", "B": "Logic states", "C": "Digital codes", "D": "Traffic nodes"}}, {"qid": "T6C13", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following is accurately represented in electrical circuit schematic diagrams?", "options": {"A": "Wire lengths", "B": "Physical appearance of components", "C": "The way components are interconnected", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T6D01", "answer": "B", "question": "Which of the following devices or circuits changes an alternating current into a varying direct current signal?", "options": {"A": "Transformer", "B": "Rectifier", "C": "Amplifier", "D": "Reflector"}}, {"qid": "T6D02", "answer": "A", "question": "What best describes a relay?", "options": {"A": "A switch controlled by an electromagnet", "B": "A current controlled amplifier", "C": "An optical sensor", "D": "A pass transistor"}}, {"qid": "T6D03", "answer": "A", "question": "What type of switch is represented by component 3 in figure T2?", "options": {"A": "Single-pole single-throw", "B": "Single-pole double-throw", "C": "Double-pole single-throw", "D": "Double-pole double-throw"}}, {"qid": "T6D04", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following can be used to display signal strength on a numeric scale?", "options": {"A": "Potentiometer", "B": "Transistor", "C": "Meter", "D": "Relay"}}, {"qid": "T6D05", "answer": "A", "question": "What type of circuit controls the amount of voltage from a power supply?", "options": {"A": "Regulator", "B": "Oscillator", "C": "Filter", "D": "Phase inverter"}}, {"qid": "T6D06", "answer": "B", "question": "What component is commonly used to change 120V AC house current to a lower AC voltage for other uses?", "options": {"A": "Variable capacitor", "B": "Transformer", "C": "Transistor", "D": "Diode"}}, {"qid": "T6D07", "answer": "A", "question": "Which of the following is commonly used as a visual indicator?", "options": {"A": "LED", "B": "FET", "C": "Zener diode", "D": "Bipolar transistor"}}, {"qid": "T6D08", "answer": "D", "question": "Which of the following is used together with an inductor to make a tuned circuit?", "options": {"A": "Resistor", "B": "Zener diode", "C": "Potentiometer", "D": "Capacitor"}}, {"qid": "T6D09", "answer": "C", "question": "What is the name of a device that combines several semiconductors and other components into one package?", "options": {"A": "Transducer", "B": "Multi-pole relay", "C": "Integrated circuit", "D": "Transformer"}}, {"qid": "T6D10", "answer": "C", "question": "What is the function of component 2 in Figure T1?", "options": {"A": "Give off light when current flows through it", "B": "Supply electrical energy", "C": "Control the flow of current", "D": "Convert electrical energy into radio waves"}}, {"qid": "T6D11", "answer": "A", "question": "What is a simple resonant or tuned circuit?", "options": {"A": "An inductor and a capacitor connected in series or parallel to form a filter", "B": "A type of voltage regulator", "C": "A resistor circuit used for reducing standing wave ratio", "D": "A circuit designed to provide high fidelity audio"}}, {"qid": "T6D12", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following is a common reason to use shielded wire?", "options": {"A": "To decrease the resistance of DC power connections", "B": "To increase the current carrying capability of the wire", "C": "To prevent coupling of unwanted signals to or from the wire", "D": "To couple the wire to other signals"}}, {"qid": "T7A01", "answer": "B", "question": "B.\ufffdSensitivity", "options": {"C": "Selectivity", "D": "Total Harmonic Distortion"}}, {"qid": "T7A02", "answer": "B", "question": "A.\ufffdA type of antenna switch", "options": {"B": "A unit combining the functions of a transmitter and a receiver", "C": "A component in a repeater which filters out unwanted interference", "D": "A type of antenna matching network"}}, {"qid": "T7A03", "answer": "B", "question": "Which of the following is used to convert a radio signal from one frequency to another?", "options": {"A": "Phase splitter", "B": "Mixer", "C": "Inverter", "D": "Amplifier"}}, {"qid": "T7A04", "answer": "C", "question": "Which term describes the ability of a receiver to discriminate between multiple signals?", "options": {"A": "Discrimination ratio", "B": "Sensitivity", "C": "Selectivity", "D": "Harmonic Distortion"}}, {"qid": "T7A05", "answer": "D", "question": "What is the name of a circuit that generates a signal of a desired frequency?", "options": {"A": "Reactance modulator", "B": "Product detector", "C": "Low-pass filter", "D": "Oscillator"}}, {"qid": "T7A06", "answer": "C", "question": "What device takes the output of a low-powered 28 MHz SSB exciter and produces a 222 MHz output signal?", "options": {"A": "High-pass filter", "B": "Low-pass filter", "C": "Transverter", "D": "Phase converter"}}, {"qid": "T7A07", "answer": "D", "question": "What is meant by term \ufffdPTT\ufffd?", "options": {"A": "Pre-transmission tuning to reduce transmitter harmonic emission", "B": "Precise tone transmissions used to limit repeater access to only certain signals", "C": "A primary transformer tuner use to match antennas", "D": "The push to talk function which switches between receive and transmit"}}, {"qid": "T7A08", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following describes combining speech with an RF carrier signal?-", "options": {"A": "Impedance matching", "B": "Oscillation", "C": "Modulation", "D": "Low-pass filtering"}}, {"qid": "T7A09", "answer": "B", "question": "Which of the following devices is most useful for VHF weak-signal communication?", "options": {"A": "A quarter-wave vertical antenna", "B": "A multi-mode VHF transceiver", "C": "An omni-directional antenna", "D": "A mobile VHF FM transceiver"}}, {"qid": "T7A10", "answer": "B", "question": "What device increases the low-power output from a handheld transceiver?", "options": {"A": "A voltage divider", "B": "An RF power amplifier", "C": "An impedance network", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T7A11", "answer": "A", "question": "Where is an RF preamplifier installed?", "options": {"A": "Between the antenna and receiver", "B": "At the output of the transmitter's power amplifier", "C": "Between a transmitter and antenna tuner", "D": "At the receiver's audio output"}}, {"qid": "T7B01", "answer": "D", "question": "What can you do if you are told your FM handheld or mobile transceiver is over-deviating?", "options": {"A": "Talk louder into the microphone", "B": "Let the transceiver cool off", "C": "Change to a higher power level", "D": "Talk farther away from the microphone"}}, {"qid": "T7B02", "answer": "A", "question": "What would cause a broadcast AM or FM radio to receive an amateur radio transmission unintentionally?", "options": {"A": "The receiver is unable to reject strong signals outside the AM or FM band", "B": "The microphone gain of the transmitter is turned up too high", "C": "The audio amplifier of the transmitter is overloaded", "D": "The deviation of an FM transmitter is set too low"}}, {"qid": "T7B03", "answer": "D", "question": "Which of the following may be a cause of radio frequency interference?", "options": {"A": "Fundamental overload", "B": "Harmonics", "C": "Spurious emissions", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T7B04", "answer": "D", "question": "Which of the following is a way to reduce or eliminate interference by an amateur transmitter to a nearby telephone?", "options": {"A": "Put a filter on the amateur transmitter", "B": "Reduce the microphone gain", "C": "Reduce the SWR on the transmitter transmission line", "D": "Put a RF filter on the telephone"}}, {"qid": "T7B05", "answer": "A", "question": "How can overload of a non-amateur radio or TV receiver by an amateur signal be reduced or eliminated?", "options": {"A": "Block the amateur signal with a filter at the antenna input of the affected receiver", "B": "Block the interfering signal with a filter on the amateur transmitter", "C": "Switch the transmitter from FM to SSB", "D": "Switch the transmitter to a narrow-band mode"}}, {"qid": "T7B06", "answer": "A", "question": "Which of the following actions should you take if a neighbor tells you that your station\ufffds transmissions are interfering with their radio or TV reception?", "options": {"A": "Make sure that your station is functioning properly and that it does not cause interference to your own radio or television when it is tuned to the same channel", "B": "Immediately turn off your transmitter and contact the nearest FCC office for assistance", "C": "Tell them that your license gives you the right to transmit and nothing can be done to reduce the interference", "D": "Install a harmonic doubler on the output of your transmitter and tune it until the interference is eliminated"}}, {"qid": "T7B07", "answer": "D", "question": "Which of the following may be useful in correcting a radio frequency interference problem?", "options": {"A": "Snap-on ferrite chokes", "B": "Low-pass and high-pass filters", "C": "Band-reject and band-pass filters", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T7B08", "answer": "D", "question": "What should you do if something in a neighbor\ufffds home is causing harmful interference to your amateur station?", "options": {"A": "Work with your neighbor to identify the offending device", "B": "Politely inform your neighbor about the rules that prohibit the use of devices which cause interference", "C": "Check your station and make sure it meets the standards of good amateur practice", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T7B09", "answer": "A", "question": "What is a Part 15 device?", "options": {"A": "An unlicensed device that may emit low powered radio signals on frequencies used by a licensed service", "B": "A type of amateur radio that can legally be used in the citizen\ufffds band", "C": "A device for long distance communications using special codes sanctioned by the International Amateur Radio Union", "D": "A type of test set used to determine whether a transmitter is in compliance with FCC regulation 91.15"}}, {"qid": "T7B10", "answer": "D", "question": "What might be the problem if you receive a report that your audio signal through the repeater is distorted or unintelligible?", "options": {"A": "Your transmitter may be slightly off frequency", "B": "Your batteries may be running low", "C": "You could be in a bad location", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T7B11", "answer": "C", "question": "What is a symptom of RF feedback in a transmitter or transceiver?", "options": {"A": "Excessive SWR at the antenna connection", "B": "The transmitter will not stay on the desired frequency", "C": "Reports of garbled, distorted, or unintelligible transmissions", "D": "Frequent blowing of power supply fuses"}}, {"qid": "T7B12", "answer": "D", "question": "What might be the first step to resolve cable TV interference from your ham radio transmission?", "options": {"A": "Add a low pass filter to the TV antenna input", "B": "Add a high pass filter to the TV antenna input", "C": "Add a preamplifier to the TV antenna input", "D": "Be sure all TV coaxial connectors are installed properly"}}, {"qid": "T7C01", "answer": "A", "question": "What is the primary purpose of a dummy load?", "options": {"A": "To prevent the radiation of signals when making tests", "B": "To prevent over-modulation of your transmitter", "C": "To improve the radiation from your antenna", "D": "To improve the signal to noise ratio of your receiver"}}, {"qid": "T7C02", "answer": "B", "question": "Which of the following instruments can be used to determine if an antenna is resonant at the desired operating frequency?", "options": {"A": "A VTVM", "B": "An antenna analyzer", "C": "A Q meter", "D": "A frequency counter"}}, {"qid": "T7C03", "answer": "A", "question": "What, in general terms, is standing wave ratio (SWR)?", "options": {"A": "A measure of how well a load is matched to a transmission line", "B": "The ratio of high to low impedance in a feed line", "C": "The transmitter efficiency ratio", "D": "An indication of the quality of your station\ufffds ground connection"}}, {"qid": "T7C04", "answer": "C", "question": "What reading on an SWR meter indicates a perfect impedance match between the antenna and the feed line?", "options": {"A": "2 to 1", "B": "1 to 3", "C": "1 to 1", "D": "10 to 1"}}, {"qid": "T7C05", "answer": "A", "question": "What is the approximate SWR value above which the protection circuits in most solid-state transmitters begin to reduce transmitter power?", "options": {"A": "2 to 1", "B": "1 to 2", "C": "6 to 1", "D": "10 to 1"}}, {"qid": "T7C06", "answer": "D", "question": "What does an SWR reading of 4:1 indicate?", "options": {"A": "Loss of -4dB", "B": "Good impedance match", "C": "Gain of +4dB", "D": "Impedance mismatch"}}, {"qid": "T7C07", "answer": "C", "question": "What happens to power lost in a feed line?", "options": {"A": "It increases the SWR", "B": "It comes back into your transmitter and could cause damage", "C": "It is converted into heat", "D": "It can cause distortion of your signal"}}, {"qid": "T7C08", "answer": "D", "question": "What instrument other than an SWR meter could you use to determine if a feed line and antenna are properly matched?", "options": {"A": "Voltmeter", "B": "Ohmmeter", "C": "Iambic pentameter", "D": "Directional wattmeter"}}, {"qid": "T7C09", "answer": "A", "question": "Which of the following is the most common cause for failure of coaxial cables?", "options": {"A": "Moisture contamination", "B": "Gamma rays", "C": "The velocity factor exceeds 1.0", "D": "Overloading"}}, {"qid": "T7C10", "answer": "D", "question": "Why should the outer jacket of coaxial cable be resistant to ultraviolet light?", "options": {"A": "Ultraviolet resistant jackets prevent harmonic radiation", "B": "Ultraviolet light can increase losses in the cable\ufffds jacket", "C": "Ultraviolet and RF signals can mix together, causing interference", "D": "Ultraviolet light can damage the jacket and allow water to enter the cable"}}, {"qid": "T7C11", "answer": "C", "question": "What is a disadvantage of air core coaxial cable when compared to foam or solid dielectric types?", "options": {"A": "It has more loss per foot", "B": "It cannot be used for VHF or UHF antennas", "C": "It requires special techniques to prevent water absorption", "D": "It cannot be used at below freezing temperatures"}}, {"qid": "T7C12", "answer": "B", "question": "Which of the following is a common use of coaxial cable?", "options": {"A": "Carrying dc power from a vehicle battery to a mobile radio", "B": "Carrying RF signals between a radio and antenna", "C": "Securing masts, tubing, and other cylindrical objects on towers", "D": "Connecting data signals from a TNC to a computer"}}, {"qid": "T7C13", "answer": "B", "question": "What does a dummy load consist of?", "options": {"A": "A high-gain amplifier and a TR switch", "B": "A non-inductive resistor and a heat sink", "C": "A low voltage power supply and a DC relay", "D": "A 50 ohm reactance used to terminate a transmission line"}}, {"qid": "T7D01", "answer": "B", "question": "Which instrument would you use to measure electric potential or electromotive force?", "options": {"A": "An ammeter", "B": "A voltmeter", "C": "A wavemeter", "D": "An ohmmeter"}}, {"qid": "T7D02", "answer": "B", "question": "What is the correct way to connect a voltmeter to a circuit?", "options": {"A": "In series with the circuit", "B": "In parallel with the circuit", "C": "In quadrature with the circuit", "D": "In phase with the circuit"}}, {"qid": "T7D03", "answer": "A", "question": "How is an ammeter usually connected to a circuit?", "options": {"A": "In series with the circuit", "B": "In parallel with the circuit", "C": "In quadrature with the circuit", "D": "In phase with the circuit"}}, {"qid": "T7D04", "answer": "D", "question": "Which instrument is used to measure electric current?", "options": {"A": "An ohmmeter", "B": "A wavemeter", "C": "A voltmeter", "D": "An ammeter"}}, {"qid": "T7D05", "answer": "D", "question": "What instrument is used to measure resistance?", "options": {"A": "An oscilloscope", "B": "A spectrum analyzer", "C": "A noise bridge", "D": "An ohmmeter"}}, {"qid": "T7D06", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following might damage a multimeter?", "options": {"A": "Measuring a voltage too small for the chosen scale", "B": "Leaving the meter in the milliamps position overnight", "C": "Attempting to measure voltage when using the resistance setting", "D": "Not allowing it to warm up properly"}}, {"qid": "T7D07", "answer": "D", "question": "Which of the following measurements are commonly made using a multimeter?", "options": {"A": "SWR and RF power", "B": "Signal strength and noise", "C": "Impedance and reactance", "D": "Voltage and resistance"}}, {"qid": "T7D08", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following types of solder is best for radio and electronic use?", "options": {"A": "Acid-core solder", "B": "Silver solder", "C": "Rosin-core solder", "D": "Aluminum solder"}}, {"qid": "T7D09", "answer": "C", "question": "What is the characteristic appearance of a cold solder joint?", "options": {"A": "Dark black spots", "B": "A bright or shiny surface", "C": "A grainy or dull surface", "D": "A greenish tint"}}, {"qid": "T7D10", "answer": "B", "question": "What is probably happening when an ohmmeter, connected across an unpowered circuit, initially indicates a low resistance and then shows increasing resistance with time?", "options": {"A": "The ohmmeter is defective", "B": "The circuit contains a large capacitor", "C": "The circuit contains a large inductor", "D": "The circuit is a relaxation oscillator"}}, {"qid": "T7D11", "answer": "B", "question": "Which of the following precautions should be taken when measuring circuit resistance with an ohmmeter?", "options": {"A": "Ensure that the applied voltages are correct", "B": "Ensure that the circuit is not powered", "C": "Ensure that the circuit is grounded", "D": "Ensure that the circuit is operating at the correct frequency"}}, {"qid": "T7D12", "answer": "B", "question": "Which of the following precautions should be taken when measuring high voltages with a voltmeter?", "options": {"A": "Ensure that the voltmeter has very low impedance", "B": "Ensure that the voltmeter and leads are rated for use at the voltages to be measured", "C": "Ensure that the circuit is grounded through the voltmeter", "D": "Ensure that the voltmeter is set to the correct frequency"}}, {"qid": "T8A01", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following is a form of amplitude modulation?", "options": {"A": "Spread-spectrum", "B": "Packet radio", "C": "Single sideband", "D": "Phase shift keying"}}, {"qid": "T8A02", "answer": "A", "question": "What type of modulation is most commonly used for VHF packet radio transmissions?", "options": {"A": "FM", "B": "SSB", "C": "AM", "D": "Spread Spectrum"}}, {"qid": "T8A03", "answer": "C", "question": "Which type of voice mode is most often used for long-distance (weak signal) contacts on the VHF and UHF bands?", "options": {"A": "FM", "B": "DRM", "C": "SSB", "D": "PM"}}, {"qid": "T8A04", "answer": "D", "question": "Which type of modulation is most commonly used for VHF and UHF voice repeaters?", "options": {"A": "AM", "B": "SSB", "C": "PSK", "D": "FM"}}, {"qid": "T8A05", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following types of emission has the narrowest bandwidth?", "options": {"A": "FM voice", "B": "SSB voice", "C": "CW", "D": "Slow-scan TV"}}, {"qid": "T8A06", "answer": "A", "question": "Which sideband is normally used for 10 meter HF, VHF and UHF single-sideband communications?", "options": {"A": "Upper sideband", "B": "Lower sideband", "C": "Suppressed sideband", "D": "Inverted sideband"}}, {"qid": "T8A07", "answer": "C", "question": "What is the primary advantage of single sideband over FM for voice transmissions?", "options": {"A": "SSB signals are easier to tune", "B": "SSB signals are less susceptible to interference", "C": "SSB signals have narrower bandwidth", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T8A08", "answer": "B", "question": "What is the approximate bandwidth of a single sideband voice signal?", "options": {"A": "1 kHz", "B": "3 kHz", "C": "6 kHz", "D": "15 kHz"}}, {"qid": "T8A09", "answer": "C", "question": "What is the approximate bandwidth of a VHF repeater FM phone signal?", "options": {"A": "Less than 500 Hz", "B": "About 150 kHz", "C": "Between 10 and 15 kHz", "D": "Between 50 and 125 kHz"}}, {"qid": "T8A10", "answer": "B", "question": "What is the typical bandwidth of analog fast-scan TV transmissions on the 70 cm band?", "options": {"A": "More than 10 MHz", "B": "About 6 MHz", "C": "About 3 MHz", "D": "About 1 MHz"}}, {"qid": "T8A11", "answer": "B", "question": "What is the approximate maximum bandwidth required to transmit a CW signal?", "options": {"A": "2.4 kHz", "B": "150 Hz", "C": "1000 Hz", "D": "15 kHz"}}, {"qid": "T8B01", "answer": "D", "question": "Who may be the control operator of a station communicating through an amateur satellite or space station?", "options": {"A": "Only an Amateur Extra Class operator", "B": "A General Class licensee or higher licensee who has a satellite operator certification", "C": "Only an Amateur Extra Class operator who is also an AMSAT member", "D": "Any amateur whose license privileges allow them to transmit on the satellite uplink frequency"}}, {"qid": "T8B02", "answer": "B", "question": "How much transmitter power should be used on the uplink frequency of an amateur satellite or space station?", "options": {"A": "The maximum power of your transmitter", "B": "The minimum amount of power needed to complete the contact", "C": "No more than half the rating of your linear amplifier", "D": "Never more than 1 watt"}}, {"qid": "T8B03", "answer": "D", "question": "Which of the following are provided by satellite tracking programs?", "options": {"A": "Maps showing the real-time position of the satellite track over the earth", "B": "The time, azimuth, and elevation of the start, maximum altitude, and end of a pass", "C": "The apparent frequency of the satellite transmission, including effects of Doppler shift", "D": "All of these answers are correct"}}, {"qid": "T8B04", "answer": "B", "question": "Which amateur stations may make contact with an amateur station on the International Space Station using 2 meter and 70 cm band amateur radio frequencies?", "options": {"A": "Only members of amateur radio clubs at NASA facilities", "B": "Any amateur holding a Technician or higher class license", "C": "Only the astronaut's family members who are hams", "D": "You cannot talk to the ISS on amateur radio frequencies"}}, {"qid": "T8B05", "answer": "D", "question": "What is a satellite beacon?", "options": {"A": "The primary transmit antenna on the satellite", "B": "An indicator light that that shows where to point your antenna", "C": "A reflective surface on the satellite", "D": "A transmission from a space station that contains information about a satellite"}}, {"qid": "T8B06", "answer": "B", "question": "Which of the following are inputs to a satellite tracking program?", "options": {"A": "The weight of the satellite", "B": "The Keplerian elements", "C": "The last observed time of zero Doppler shift", "D": "All of these answers are correct"}}, {"qid": "T8B07", "answer": "C", "question": "With regard to satellite communications, what is Doppler shift?", "options": {"A": "A change in the satellite orbit", "B": "A mode where the satellite receives signals on one band and transmits on another", "C": "An observed change in signal frequency caused by relative motion between the satellite and the earth station", "D": "A special digital communications mode for some satellites"}}, {"qid": "T8B08", "answer": "B", "question": "What is meant by the statement that a satellite is operating in mode U/V?", "options": {"A": "The satellite uplink is in the 15 meter band and the downlink is in the 10 meter band", "B": "The satellite uplink is in the 70 cm band and the downlink is in the 2 meter band", "C": "The satellite operates using ultraviolet frequencies", "D": "The satellite frequencies are usually variable"}}, {"qid": "T8B09", "answer": "B", "question": "What causes spin fading when referring to satellite signals?", "options": {"A": "Circular polarized noise interference radiated from the sun", "B": "Rotation of the satellite and its antennas", "C": "Doppler shift of the received signal", "D": "Interfering signals within the satellite uplink band"}}, {"qid": "T8B10", "answer": "C", "question": "What do the initials LEO tell you about an amateur satellite?", "options": {"A": "The satellite battery is in Low Energy Operation mode", "B": "The satellite is performing a Lunar Ejection Orbit maneuver", "C": "The satellite is in a Low Earth Orbit", "D": "The satellite uses Light Emitting Optics"}}, {"qid": "T8B11", "answer": "C", "question": "What is a commonly used method of sending signals to and from a digital satellite?", "options": {"A": "USB AFSK", "B": "PSK31", "C": "FM Packet", "D": "WSJT"}}, {"qid": "T8C01", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following methods is used to locate sources of noise interference or jamming?", "options": {"A": "Echolocation", "B": "Doppler radar", "C": "Radio direction finding", "D": "Phase locking"}}, {"qid": "T8C02", "answer": "B", "question": "Which of these items would be useful for a hidden transmitter hunt?", "options": {"A": "Calibrated SWR meter", "B": "A directional antenna", "C": "A calibrated noise bridge", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T8C03", "answer": "A", "question": "What popular operating activity involves contacting as many stations as possible during a specified period of time?", "options": {"A": "Contesting", "B": "Net operations", "C": "Public service events", "D": "Simulated emergency exercises"}}, {"qid": "T8C04", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following is good procedure when contacting another station in a radio contest?", "options": {"A": "Be sure to sign only the last two letters of your call if there is a pileup calling the station", "B": "Work the station twice to be sure that you are in his log", "C": "Send only the minimum information needed for proper identification and the contest exchange", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T8C05", "answer": "A", "question": "What is a grid locator?", "options": {"A": "A letter-number designator assigned to a geographic location", "B": "A letter-number designator assigned to an azimuth and elevation", "C": "An instrument for neutralizing a final amplifier", "D": "An instrument for radio direction finding"}}, {"qid": "T8C06", "answer": "B", "question": "How is access to an IRLP node accomplished?", "options": {"A": "By obtaining a password which is sent via voice to the node", "B": "By using DTMF signals", "C": "By entering the proper Internet password", "D": "By using CTCSS tone codes"}}, {"qid": "T8C07", "answer": "B", "question": "What is the maximum power allowed when transmitting telecommand signals to radio controlled models?", "options": {"A": "500 milliwatts", "B": "1 watt", "C": "25 watts", "D": "1500 watts"}}, {"qid": "T8C08", "answer": "C", "question": "What is required in place of on-air station identification when sending signals to a radio control model using amateur frequencies?", "options": {"A": "Voice identification must be transmitted every 10 minutes", "B": "Morse code ID must be sent once per hour", "C": "A label indicating the licensee\ufffds name, call sign and address must be affixed to the transmitter", "D": "A flag must be affixed to the transmitter antenna with the station call sign in 1 inch high letters or larger"}}, {"qid": "T8C09", "answer": "C", "question": "How might you obtain a list of active nodes that use VoIP?", "options": {"A": "From the FCC Rulebook", "B": "From your local emergency coordinator", "C": "From a repeater directory", "D": "From the local repeater frequency coordinator"}}, {"qid": "T8C10", "answer": "D", "question": "How do you select a specific IRLP node when using a portable transceiver?", "options": {"A": "Choose a specific CTCSS tone", "B": "Choose the correct DSC tone", "C": "Access the repeater autopatch", "D": "Use the keypad to transmit the IRLP node ID"}}, {"qid": "T8C11", "answer": "A", "question": "What name is given to an amateur radio station that is used to connect other amateur stations to the Internet?", "options": {"A": "A gateway", "B": "A repeater", "C": "A digipeater", "D": "A beacon"}}, {"qid": "T8C12", "answer": "D", "question": "What is meant by Voice Over Internet Protocol (VoIP) as used in amateur radio?", "options": {"A": "A set of rules specifying how to identify your station when linked over the Internet to another station", "B": "A set of guidelines for working DX during contests using Internet access", "C": "A technique for measuring the modulation quality of a transmitter using remote sites monitored via the Internet", "D": "A method of delivering voice communications over the Internet using digital techniques"}}, {"qid": "T8C13", "answer": "A", "question": "What is the Internet Radio Linking Project (IRLP)?", "options": {"A": "A technique to connect amateur radio systems, such as repeaters, via the Internet using Voice Over Internet Protocol", "B": "A system for providing access to websites via amateur radio", "C": "A system for informing amateurs in real time of the frequency of active DX stations", "D": "A technique for measuring signal strength of an amateur transmitter via the Internet"}}, {"qid": "T8D01", "answer": "D", "question": "Which of the following is an example of a digital communications method?", "options": {"A": "Packet", "B": "PSK31", "C": "MFSK", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T8D02", "answer": "A", "question": "What does the term \ufffdAPRS\ufffd mean?", "options": {"A": "Automatic Packet Reporting System", "B": "Associated Public Radio Station", "C": "Auto Planning Radio Set-up", "D": "Advanced Polar Radio System"}}, {"qid": "T8D03", "answer": "D", "question": "Which of the following devices provides data to the transmitter when sending automatic position reports from a mobile amateur radio station?", "options": {"A": "The vehicle speedometer", "B": "A WWV receiver", "C": "A connection to a broadcast FM sub-carrier receiver", "D": "A Global Positioning System receiver"}}, {"qid": "T8D04", "answer": "C", "question": "What type of transmission is indicated by the term NTSC?", "options": {"A": "A Normal Transmission mode in Static Circuit", "B": "A special mode for earth satellite uplink", "C": "An analog fast scan color TV signal", "D": "A frame compression scheme for TV signals"}}, {"qid": "T8D05", "answer": "A", "question": "Which of the following is an application of APRS (Automatic Packet Reporting System)?", "options": {"A": "Providing real time tactical digital communications in conjunction with a map showing the locations of stations", "B": "Showing automatically the number of packets transmitted via PACTOR during a specific time interval", "C": "Providing voice over Internet connection between repeaters", "D": "Providing information on the number of stations signed into a repeater"}}, {"qid": "T8D06", "answer": "B", "question": "What does the abbreviation PSK mean?", "options": {"A": "Pulse Shift Keying", "B": "Phase Shift Keying", "C": "Packet Short Keying", "D": "Phased Slide Keying"}}, {"qid": "T8D07", "answer": "D", "question": "What is PSK31?", "options": {"A": "A high-rate data transmission mode", "B": "A method of reducing noise interference to FM signals", "C": "A method of compressing digital television signals", "D": "A low-rate data transmission mode"}}, {"qid": "T8D08", "answer": "D", "question": "Which of the following may be included in packet transmissions?", "options": {"A": "A check sum which permits error detection", "B": "A header which contains the call sign of the station to which the information is being sent", "C": "Automatic repeat request in case of error", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T8D09", "answer": "C", "question": "What code is used when sending CW in the amateur bands?", "options": {"A": "Baudot", "B": "Hamming", "C": "International Morse", "D": "Gray"}}, {"qid": "T8D10", "answer": "D", "question": "Which of the following can be used to transmit CW in the amateur bands?", "options": {"A": "Straight Key", "B": "Electronic Keyer", "C": "Computer Keyboard", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T8D11", "answer": "C", "question": "What is an ARQ transmission system?", "options": {"A": "A special transmission format limited to video signals", "B": "A system used to encrypt command signals to an amateur radio satellite", "C": "A digital scheme whereby the receiving station detects errors and sends a request to the sending station to retransmit the information", "D": "A method of compressing the data in a message so more information can be sent in a shorter time"}}, {"qid": "T9A01", "answer": "C", "question": "What is a beam antenna?", "options": {"A": "An antenna built from aluminum I-beams", "B": "An omnidirectional antenna invented by Clarence Beam", "C": "An antenna that concentrates signals in one direction", "D": "An antenna that reverses the phase of received signals"}}, {"qid": "T9A02", "answer": "B", "question": "Which of the following is true regarding vertical antennas?", "options": {"A": "The magnetic field is perpendicular to the Earth", "B": "The electric field is perpendicular to the Earth", "C": "The phase is inverted", "D": "The phase is reversed"}}, {"qid": "T9A03", "answer": "B", "question": "Which of the following describes a simple dipole mounted so the conductor is parallel to the Earth's surface?", "options": {"A": "A ground wave antenna", "B": "A horizontally polarized antenna", "C": "A rhombic antenna", "D": "A vertically polarized antenna"}}, {"qid": "T9A04", "answer": "A", "question": "What is a disadvantage of the \ufffdrubber duck\ufffd antenna supplied with most handheld radio transceivers?", "options": {"A": "It does not transmit or receive as effectively as a full-sized antenna", "B": "It transmits a circularly polarized signal", "C": "If the rubber end cap is lost it will unravel very quickly", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T9A05", "answer": "C", "question": "How would you change a dipole antenna to make it resonant on a higher frequency?", "options": {"A": "Lengthen it", "B": "Insert coils in series with radiating wires", "C": "Shorten it", "D": "Add capacitive loading to the ends of the radiating wires"}}, {"qid": "T9A06", "answer": "C", "question": "What type of antennas are the quad, Yagi, and dish?", "options": {"A": "Non-resonant antennas", "B": "Loop antennas", "C": "Directional antennas", "D": "Isotropic antennas"}}, {"qid": "T9A07", "answer": "A", "question": "What is a good reason not to use a \ufffdrubber duck\ufffd antenna inside your car?", "options": {"A": "Signals can be significantly weaker than when it is outside of the vehicle", "B": "It might cause your radio to overheat", "C": "The SWR might decrease, decreasing the signal strength", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T9A08", "answer": "C", "question": "What is the approximate length, in inches, of a quarter-wavelength vertical antenna for 146 MHz?", "options": {"A": "112", "B": "50", "C": "19", "D": "12"}}, {"qid": "T9A09", "answer": "C", "question": "What is the approximate length, in inches, of a 6 meter 1/2-wavelength wire dipole antenna?", "options": {"A": "6", "B": "50", "C": "112", "D": "236"}}, {"qid": "T9A10", "answer": "C", "question": "In which direction is the radiation strongest from a half-wave dipole antenna in free space?", "options": {"A": "Equally in all directions", "B": "Off the ends of the antenna", "C": "Broadside to the antenna", "D": "In the direction of the feed line"}}, {"qid": "T9A11", "answer": "C", "question": "What is meant by the gain of an antenna?", "options": {"A": "The additional power that is added to the transmitter power", "B": "The additional power that is lost in the antenna when transmitting on a higher frequency", "C": "The increase in signal strength in a specified direction when compared to a reference antenna", "D": "The increase in impedance on receive or transmit compared to a reference antenna"}}, {"qid": "T9A12", "answer": "A", "question": "What is a reason to use a properly mounted 5/8 wavelength antenna for VHF or UHF mobile service?", "options": {"A": "It offers a lower angle of radiation and more gain than a 1/4 wavelength antenna and usually provides improved coverage", "B": "It features a very high angle of radiation and is better for communicating via a repeater", "C": "The 5/8 wavelength antenna completely eliminates distortion caused by reflected signals", "D": "The 5/8 wavelength antenna offers a 10-times power gain over a 1/4 wavelength design"}}, {"qid": "T9A13", "answer": "C", "question": "Why are VHF or UHF mobile antennas often mounted in the center of the vehicle roof?", "options": {"A": "Roof mounts have the lowest possible SWR of any mounting configuration", "B": "Only roof mounting can guarantee a vertically polarized signal", "C": "A roof mounted antenna normally provides the most uniform radiation pattern", "D": "Roof mounted antennas are always the easiest to install"}}, {"qid": "T9A14", "answer": "A", "question": "Which of the following terms describes a type of loading when referring to an antenna?", "options": {"A": "Inserting an inductor in the radiating portion of the antenna to make it electrically longer", "B": "Inserting a resistor in the radiating portion of the antenna to make it resonant", "C": "Installing a spring at the base of the antenna to absorb the effects of collisions with other objects", "D": "Making the antenna heavier so it will resist wind effects when in motion"}}, {"qid": "T9B01", "answer": "B", "question": "Why is it important to have a low SWR in an antenna system that uses coaxial cable feed line?", "options": {"A": "To reduce television interference", "B": "To allow the efficient transfer of power and reduce losses", "C": "To prolong antenna life", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T9B02", "answer": "B", "question": "What is the impedance of the most commonly used coaxial cable in typical amateur radio installations?", "options": {"A": "8 ohms", "B": "50 ohms", "C": "600 ohms", "D": "12 ohms"}}, {"qid": "T9B03", "answer": "A", "question": "Why is coaxial cable used more often than any other feed line for amateur radio antenna systems?", "options": {"A": "It is easy to use and requires few special installation considerations", "B": "It has less loss than any other type of feed line", "C": "It can handle more power than any other type of feed line", "D": "It is less expensive than any other types of feed line"}}, {"qid": "T9B04", "answer": "A", "question": "What does an antenna tuner do?", "options": {"A": "It matches the antenna system impedance to the transceiver's output impedance", "B": "It helps a receiver automatically tune in weak stations", "C": "It allows an antenna to be used on both transmit and receive", "D": "It automatically selects the proper antenna for the frequency band being used"}}, {"qid": "T9B05", "answer": "D", "question": "What generally happens as the frequency of a signal passing through coaxial cable is increased?", "options": {"A": "The apparent SWR increases", "B": "The reflected power increases", "C": "The characteristic impedance increases", "D": "The loss increases"}}, {"qid": "T9B06", "answer": "B", "question": "Which of the following connectors is most suitable for frequencies above 400 MHz?", "options": {"A": "A UHF (PL-259/SO-239) connector", "B": "A Type N connector", "C": "An RS-213 connector", "D": "A DB-25 connector"}}, {"qid": "T9B07", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following is true of PL-259 type coax connectors?", "options": {"A": "They are preferred for microwave operation", "B": "They are water tight", "C": "They are commonly used at HF frequencies", "D": "They are a bayonet type connector"}}, {"qid": "T9B08", "answer": "A", "question": "Why should coax connectors exposed to the weather be sealed against water intrusion?", "options": {"A": "To prevent an increase in feed line loss", "B": "To prevent interference to telephones", "C": "To keep the jacket from becoming loose", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T9B09", "answer": "B", "question": "What might cause erratic changes in SWR readings?", "options": {"A": "The transmitter is being modulated", "B": "A loose connection in an antenna or a feed line", "C": "The transmitter is being over-modulated", "D": "Interference from other stations is distorting your signal"}}, {"qid": "T9B10", "answer": "C", "question": "What electrical difference exists between the smaller RG-58 and larger RG-8 coaxial cables?", "options": {"A": "There is no significant difference between the two types", "B": "RG-58 cable has less loss at a given frequency", "C": "RG-8 cable has less loss at a given frequency", "D": "RG-58 cable can handle higher power levels"}}, {"qid": "T9B11", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following types of feed line has the lowest loss at VHF and UHF?", "options": {"A": "50-ohm flexible coax", "B": "Multi-conductor unbalanced cable", "C": "Air-insulated hard line", "D": "75-ohm flexible coax"}}, {"qid": "T0A01", "answer": "B", "question": "Which of the following is a safety hazard of a 12-volt storage battery?", "options": {"A": "Touching both terminals with the hands can cause electrical shock", "B": "Shorting the terminals can cause burns, fire, or an explosion", "C": "RF emissions from the battery", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T0A02", "answer": "D", "question": "How does current flowing through the body cause a health hazard?", "options": {"A": "By heating tissue", "B": "It disrupts the electrical functions of cells", "C": "It causes involuntary muscle contractions", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T0A03", "answer": "C", "question": "What is connected to the green wire in a three-wire electrical AC plug?", "options": {"A": "Neutral", "B": "Hot", "C": "Safety ground", "D": "The white wire"}}, {"qid": "T0A04", "answer": "B", "question": "What is the purpose of a fuse in an electrical circuit?", "options": {"A": "To prevent power supply ripple from damaging a circuit", "B": "To interrupt power in case of overload", "C": "To limit current to prevent shocks", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T0A05", "answer": "C", "question": "Why is it unwise to install a 20-ampere fuse in the place of a 5-ampere fuse?", "options": {"A": "The larger fuse would be likely to blow because it is rated for higher current", "B": "The power supply ripple would greatly increase", "C": "Excessive current could cause a fire", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T0A06", "answer": "D", "question": "What is a good way to guard against electrical shock at your station?", "options": {"A": "Use three-wire cords and plugs for all AC powered equipment", "B": "Connect all AC powered station equipment to a common safety ground", "C": "Use a circuit protected by a ground-fault interrupter", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T0A07", "answer": "D", "question": "Which of these precautions should be taken when installing devices for lightning protection in a coaxial cable feed line?", "options": {"A": "Include a parallel bypass switch for each protector so that it can be switched out of the circuit when running high power", "B": "Include a series switch in the ground line of each protector to prevent RF overload from inadvertently damaging the protector", "C": "Keep the ground wires from each protector separate and connected to station ground", "D": "Ground all of the protectors to a common plate which is in turn connected to an external ground"}}, {"qid": "T0A08", "answer": "A", "question": "What safety equipment should always be included in home-built equipment that is powered from 120V AC power circuits?", "options": {"A": "A fuse or circuit breaker in series with the AC hot conductor", "B": "An AC voltmeter across the incoming power source", "C": "An inductor in series with the AC power source", "D": "A capacitor across the AC power source"}}, {"qid": "T0A09", "answer": "C", "question": "What kind of hazard is presented by a conventional 12-volt storage battery?", "options": {"A": "It emits ozone which can be harmful to the atmosphere", "B": "Shock hazard due to high voltage", "C": "Explosive gas can collect if not properly vented", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T0A10", "answer": "A", "question": "What can happen if a lead-acid storage battery is charged or discharged too quickly?", "options": {"A": "The battery could overheat and give off flammable gas or explode", "B": "The voltage can become reversed", "C": "The memory effect will reduce the capacity of the battery", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T0A11", "answer": "D", "question": "What kind of hazard might exist in a power supply when it is turned off and disconnected?", "options": {"A": "Static electricity could damage the grounding system", "B": "Circulating currents inside the transformer might cause damage", "C": "The fuse might blow if you remove the cover", "D": "You might receive an electric shock from the charged stored in large capacitors"}}, {"qid": "T0B01", "answer": "C", "question": "When should members of a tower work team wear a hard hat and safety glasses?", "options": {"A": "At all times except when climbing the tower", "B": "At all times except when belted firmly to the tower", "C": "At all times when any work is being done on the tower", "D": "Only when the tower exceeds 30 feet in height"}}, {"qid": "T0B02", "answer": "C", "question": "What is a good precaution to observe before climbing an antenna tower?", "options": {"A": "Make sure that you wear a grounded wrist strap", "B": "Remove all tower grounding connections", "C": "Put on a climbing harness and safety glasses", "D": "All of the these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T0B03", "answer": "D", "question": "Under what circumstances is it safe to climb a tower without a helper or observer?", "options": {"A": "When no electrical work is being performed", "B": "When no mechanical work is being performed", "C": "When the work being done is not more than 20 feet above the ground", "D": "Never"}}, {"qid": "T0B04", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following is an important safety precaution to observe when putting up an antenna tower?", "options": {"A": "Wear a ground strap connected to your wrist at all times", "B": "Insulate the base of the tower to avoid lightning strikes", "C": "Look for and stay clear of any overhead electrical wires", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T0B05", "answer": "C", "question": "What is the purpose of a gin pole?", "options": {"A": "To temporarily replace guy wires", "B": "To be used in place of a safety harness", "C": "To lift tower sections or antennas", "D": "To provide a temporary ground"}}, {"qid": "T0B06", "answer": "D", "question": "What is the minimum safe distance from a power line to allow when installing an antenna?", "options": {"A": "Half the width of your property", "B": "The height of the power line above ground", "C": "1/2 wavelength at the operating frequency", "D": "So that if the antenna falls unexpectedly, no part of it can come closer than 10 feet to the power wires"}}, {"qid": "T0B07", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following is an important safety rule to remember when using a crank-up tower?", "options": {"A": "This type of tower must never be painted", "B": "This type of tower must never be grounded", "C": "This type of tower must never be climbed unless it is in the fully retracted position", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T0B08", "answer": "C", "question": "What is considered to be a proper grounding method for a tower?", "options": {"A": "A single four-foot ground rod, driven into the ground no more than 12 inches from the base", "B": "A ferrite-core RF choke connected between the tower and ground", "C": "Separate eight-foot long ground rods for each tower leg, bonded to the tower and each other", "D": "A connection between the tower base and a cold water pipe"}}, {"qid": "T0B09", "answer": "C", "question": "Why should you avoid attaching an antenna to a utility pole?", "options": {"A": "The antenna will not work properly because of induced voltages", "B": "The utility company will charge you an extra monthly fee", "C": "The antenna could contact high-voltage power wires", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T0B10", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following is true concerning grounding conductors used for lightning protection?", "options": {"A": "Only non-insulated wire must be used", "B": "Wires must be carefully routed with precise right-angle bends", "C": "Sharp bends must be avoided", "D": "Common grounds must be avoided"}}, {"qid": "T0B11", "answer": "B", "question": "Which of the following establishes grounding requirements for an amateur radio tower or antenna?", "options": {"A": "FCC Part 97 Rules", "B": "Local electrical codes", "C": "FAA tower lighting regulations", "D": "Underwriters Laboratories' recommended practices"}}, {"qid": "T0B12", "answer": "C", "question": "Which of the following is good practice when installing ground wires on a tower for lightning protection?", "options": {"A": "Put a loop in the ground connection to prevent water damage to the ground system", "B": "Make sure that all bends in the ground wires are clean, right angle bends", "C": "Ensure that connections are short and direct", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T0C01", "answer": "D", "question": "What type of radiation are VHF and UHF radio signals?", "options": {"A": "Gamma radiation", "B": "Ionizing radiation", "C": "Alpha radiation", "D": "Non-ionizing radiation"}}, {"qid": "T0C02", "answer": "B", "question": "Which of the following frequencies has the lowest value for Maximum Permissible Exposure limit?", "options": {"A": "3.5 MHz", "B": "50 MHz", "C": "440 MHz", "D": "1296 MHz"}}, {"qid": "T0C03", "answer": "C", "question": "What is the maximum power level that an amateur radio station may use at VHF frequencies before an RF exposure evaluation is required?", "options": {"A": "1500 watts PEP transmitter output", "B": "1 watt forward power", "C": "50 watts PEP at the antenna", "D": "50 watts PEP reflected power"}}, {"qid": "T0C04", "answer": "D", "question": "What factors affect the RF exposure of people near an amateur station antenna?", "options": {"A": "Frequency and power level of the RF field", "B": "Distance from the antenna to a person", "C": "Radiation pattern of the antenna", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T0C05", "answer": "D", "question": "Why do exposure limits vary with frequency?", "options": {"A": "Lower frequency RF fields have more energy than higher frequency fields", "B": "Lower frequency RF fields do not penetrate the human body", "C": "Higher frequency RF fields are transient in nature", "D": "The human body absorbs more RF energy at some frequencies than at others"}}, {"qid": "T0C06", "answer": "D", "question": "Which of the following is an acceptable method to determine that your station complies with FCC RF exposure regulations?", "options": {"A": "By calculation based on FCC OET Bulletin 65", "B": "By calculation based on computer modeling", "C": "By measurement of field strength using calibrated equipment", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T0C07", "answer": "B", "question": "What could happen if a person accidentally touched your antenna while you were transmitting?", "options": {"A": "Touching the antenna could cause television interference", "B": "They might receive a painful RF burn", "C": "They might develop radiation poisoning", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T0C08", "answer": "A", "question": "Which of the following actions might amateur operators take to prevent exposure to RF radiation in excess of FCC-supplied limits?", "options": {"A": "Relocate antennas", "B": "Relocate the transmitter", "C": "Increase the duty cycle", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T0C09", "answer": "B", "question": "How can you make sure your station stays in compliance with RF safety regulations?", "options": {"A": "By informing the FCC of any changes made in your station", "B": "By re-evaluating the station whenever an item of equipment is changed", "C": "By making sure your antennas have low SWR", "D": "All of these choices are correct"}}, {"qid": "T0C10", "answer": "A", "question": "Why is duty cycle one of the factors used to determine safe RF radiation exposure levels?", "options": {"A": "It affects the average exposure of people to radiation", "B": "It affects the peak exposure of people to radiation", "C": "It takes into account the antenna feed line loss", "D": "It takes into account the thermal effects of the final amplifier"}}, {"qid": "T0C11", "answer": "C", "question": "What is the definition of duty cycle during the averaging time for RF exposure?", "options": {"A": "The difference between the lowest power output and the highest power output of a transmitter", "B": "The difference between the PEP and average power output of a transmitter", "C": "The percentage of time that a transmitter is transmitting", "D": "The percentage of time that a transmitter is not transmitting"}}, {"qid": "T0C12", "answer": "A", "question": "How does RF radiation differ from ionizing radiation (radioactivity)?", "options": {"A": "RF radiation does not have sufficient energy to cause genetic damage", "B": "RF radiation can only be detected with an RF dosimeter", "C": "RF radiation is limited in range to a few feet", "D": "RF radiation is perfectly safe"}}, {"qid": "T0C13", "answer": "C", "question": "If the averaging time for exposure is 6 minutes, how much power density is permitted if the signal is present for 3 minutes and absent for 3 minutes rather than being present for the entire 6 minutes?", "options": {"A": "3 times as much", "B": "1/2 as much", "C": "2 times as much", "D": "There is no adjustment allowed for shorter exposure times"}}]
